<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Sensr.net Blog | Watch your Stuff!</title>
    <link>http://blog.sensr.net/categories/technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Sensr.net Blog | Watch your Stuff!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.sensr.net/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways To Minimize IoT Vulnerabilities In Your Smart Home Network</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/12/5-ways-to-minimize-iot-vulnerabilities-in-your-smart-home-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 16:35:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/12/5-ways-to-minimize-iot-vulnerabilities-in-your-smart-home-network/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/why-no-open-source-iot-firmware/&#34;&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt; (IoT) is continuing to expand and broaden its own horizons while simultaneously helping to usher people into a
future, which is brimming with all the possibilities that an interconnected world presents. There are many industries that are working to
incorporate the Internet of Things into their infrastructure. One of these industries has been the home security industry and there are many
homeowners who are no proud parents to smart homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smart home is one greatest aspects of the Internet of Things, just because of the sheer number of actions it allows you to complete through
simple commands. For instance, some people can program their homes so that their lights come on as soon as they walk through the door. There are
many benefits to the IoT, from increased efficiency to more comfortable living. However, there are some inherent vulnerabilities in the way the
Internet of Things works, and it is easy to see why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basis of the IoT is that there are several different devices connected to each other on a network, and all sharing information and relaying
data. This concept alone hints at the fact that there are multiple entryways for unauthorized users, as well as security concerns simply because
of the sheer number of interconnected devices. When it comes to homeowners who are using the IoT to power their smart home networks, how can
they minimize these IoT vulnerabilities? LetÕs take a look at some of the ways they can avert this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-proper-password-management&#34;&gt;1. Proper Password Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always best, to begin with, the basics, and one of the basics of great network security is always making sure that you are properly
managing the passwords that grant devices access to your network. The first step to proper password management is to ensure that you create
unique passwords for each of the devices that you have connected to your smart home network. In addition to this, it is best to make sure that
you change these passwords on a regular basis so that you are consistently reducing the possibility of anyone discovering them. There are many
homeowners who overlook this simple method, but it goes a long way to help keep your network secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-utilize-a-secure-firewall&#34;&gt;2. Utilize a secure Firewall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important for homeowners to realize how vulnerable their networks can be if they do not provide any form of protection. One of the best
forms of protection comes in the form of a secure firewall. It is not a smart idea to leave your network protected by a simple router.
Homeowners should invest in secure firewalls that act as safeguards to every accessible endpoint that exists on their network. Firewalls exist
to help protect your network from unauthorized access and they greatly reduce the chances of anyone successfully &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/is-your-security-camera-hacking-someone-else/&#34;&gt;hacking into your smart home
network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-security-software-updates&#34;&gt;3. Security Software Updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing software updates is quite similar to proper password management. This is because the brunt of the responsibility falls on the homeowner
to be attentive. It is important that you constantly check to see if there are software updates available for the devices that you have on your
smart home network. These software updates are an important part of ensuring that your devices continue to run smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases, manufacturers might have discovered a flaw in the device and then release a software patch meant to rectify said problem. If the
user does not take advantage of these software patches, they will most likely end up having severe network flaws and holes that a hacker can
take advantage of to gain access to their network. One of the best ways to manage security software updates is to set at least 3 monthly
reminders. That way you never fall into the trap of forgetting that you need to update your security software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-disable-additional-features&#34;&gt;4. Disable additional features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this is something that many homeowners tend to overlook, simply because they do not know this might increase the chances of their network
being made vulnerable. In most cases, smart devices have additional features that grant them access to the networks at different times without
necessarily having to go through any security verification or authorization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process makes your entire network extremely vulnerable because it gives hackers the opportunity to exploit these loopholes. When you are
setting up your smart home network, it is imperative that you identify the additional features that each device might use. If there are any that
leave your network open and accessible, make sure that you disable these features. Essentially, you want to make it as hard as possible for a
hacker to gain access to your network. The most efficient way to do this is to plug up all possible access points that could end up being taken
advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-private-network&#34;&gt;5. Private Network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things is a network of interconnected devices. It is not really a shock that this might seem lucrative to hackers. However, an
additional way to minimize the flaws of an IoT network in the smart home is to utilize private networks. The use of a private network will add
an additional layer of security for your IoT devices. Also, it is always best to keep the network that functions with your IoT devices separate
from other networks so that they do not compromise each other with the amount of data that is being transmitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IoT on a smart home network really changes the way a home can operate, and it increases the amount of possible things that any homeowner can
accomplish. The benefits of the IoT are very likely endless, as we are only just scratching the surface. However, there are some vulnerabilities
that exist, much like anything else, so it is crucial for homeowners to make sure that they are safe guarding themselves against any of these
vulnerabilities. You may think that this is a high level of paranoia, but it is important to remember that if someone is able to gain access to
one device on an IoT network, they will most likely gain access to your entire network simply by piggybacking off of the compromised device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steps mentioned above will help keep your smart home network safe, but do not forget that physical security also plays an important role in
stemming inherent network vulnerabilities. As a homeowner, make sure that you discuss your home security with a security professional or a
residential locksmith, they will be able to help you with &lt;a href=&#34;http://united-locksmith.net/home-locksmith/smart-lock-installation&#34;&gt;smart lock installations&lt;/a&gt; as well as help you keep your home safe and secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;author-bio&#34;&gt;Author Bio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ralph Goodman is a professional writer and the resident expert on locks and security over at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://united-locksmith.net/blog&#34;&gt;Lock Blog&lt;/a&gt;. The Lock Blog is a great
resource to learn about keys, locks and safety. They offer tips, advice and how-to&amp;rsquo;s for consumers, locksmiths, and security professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why no open source IoT Firmware?</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/why-no-open-source-iot-firmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 20:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/why-no-open-source-iot-firmware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Dans les entrailles urbaines / In the urban bowels&#34; href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/m43photos/12239139316/in/photolist-jDwMHo-cxs18J-fAiNqu-dgqBrp-8JiYae-zJCUs-5hmBet-ciyJEf-aqSgjf-4zhcab-e6MK4D-3dqLhP-qP2FY-9u9Vmd-aqrFT2-6F34w2-5NAo8e-5M2nnt-cxt85q-2zrJy9-7aUP9A-5NEEK7-deB66G-bEtv1q-dksYJC-c7gy4E-rU8r9v-5S8j7P-bToeAP-6F7cKq-5NEEMf-6F7d5b-dNifDu-3bsbWr-6F7cUA-5NAoan-5NEEfh-ckh731-5NAod6-sNL1k-8DkNxR-skKu3-sGNzi-8B9Dfe-4Poqgd-cv5hA5-cvgpHu-iH8cKJ-jSg8jZ-dgSE9g&#34; data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5524/12239139316_6e97104ce8_k.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dans les entrailles urbaines / In the urban bowels&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;334&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IoT (Internet of Things) is taking off. We&amp;rsquo;re coming up with all kinds of internet connected devices. Many of these devices are simply computers with interesting sensors and controllers attached. At Sensr.net we think mostly about IP cameras, which are a specific kind of IoT device. But that &lt;a href=&#34;https://nest.com/thermostat/meet-nest-thermostat/&#34; title=&#34;Nest Thermostat&#34;&gt;Nest thermostat&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Echo-Bluetooth-Speaker-with-WiFi-Alexa/dp/B00X4WHP5E&#34; title=&#34;Amazon Echo&#34;&gt;Amazon Echo speaker&lt;/a&gt; are also examples of IoT devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days most IP cameras will connect to your internet via WiFi or Ethernet and allow you to view and control the camera remotely. Many of these cameras include a P2P (peer to peer) feature that allows you to view the camera directly even if you don&amp;rsquo;t open your firewall. This is a neat trick which is accomplished by having the camera keep open a connection back to some well known server. When you want to connect to your camera, you&amp;rsquo;re really connecting to some remote server (in China maybe?) that then does some network magic (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/STUN&#34; title=&#34;STUN: Session Traversal Utilities for NAT&#34;&gt;STUN&lt;/a&gt;) and lets your smartphone app connect to your camera through your firewall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That nice P2P feature is pretty great, but it also means that there are servers out there on the net that can get inside your home network. Where are those servers running? Who&amp;rsquo;s job is it to make sure they are secure? Who has access to those servers and thus your network and even your cameras?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-your-cams-are-belong-to-us&#34;&gt;All your cams are belong to us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Mostly we&amp;rsquo;re pretty cavalier about connecting cool new gadgets to our networks. Maybe we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be. It seems like there ought to be some way to make sure the devices you trust are actually trustworthy. How can we be sure that our security cameras are actually secure? (Warning: &lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2016/10/19/is-your-security-camera-hacking-someone-else/&#34; title=&#34;Cameras hacked into botnets&#34;&gt;They probably aren&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truthiness-in-our-firmware&#34;&gt;Truthiness in our firmware?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these devices run an operating system of some kind embedded down in their firmware. What if we created an open source firmware that we could trust? We could buy fun cheap hardware from our friends in China but then install our own good old open source code on that hardware instead of trusting the glop that came on it. Don&amp;rsquo;t want your camera connecting out some potentially compromised P2P jumphost somewhere? No problem! Just install your own firmware and configure your own jumphost or maybe one run by a company you trust. (This could be a new business opportunity for &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net: Watch your stuff!&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; maybe&amp;#8230;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-say-tomato-6-8230&#34;&gt;You say &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tomato_(firmware)&#34; title=&#34;Tomato Firmware&#34;&gt;tomato&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one successful example of this, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dd-wrt.com/site/index&#34; title=&#34;DD-WRT Site&#34;&gt;DD-WRT software&lt;/a&gt; that runs on a large number of routers.  There are a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_router_firmware_projects&#34; title=&#34;Router Firmware&#34;&gt;open source firmwares&lt;/a&gt; out there. Why can&amp;rsquo;t we have one for cameras? Or more generally IoT devices?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-together-now&#34;&gt;All together now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in joining an effort along these lines, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@sensr.net?Subject=Open%20firmware&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;drop me an email&lt;/a&gt; or contribute to the project on Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sensrnet/sensros&#34; title=&#34;SensrOS: Open source IP Camera Firmware&#34;&gt;https://github.com/sensrnet/sensros&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of cool things that could be built into this firmware.  Imagine the machine learning projects or advanced image recognition that could be built into something like this. More basic things could be done too, like reference designs for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onvif.org/&#34; title=&#34;ONVIF&#34;&gt;ONVIF&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psialliance.org/&#34; title=&#34;Physical Security Interoperability Alliance&#34;&gt;PSIA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is your security camera hacking someone else?</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/is-your-security-camera-hacking-someone-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 18:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/is-your-security-camera-hacking-someone-else/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3207&#34; style=&#34;width: 768px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3207&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2016/10/wsjscreenshot-1024x5741.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Who watches the watchers?&#34; width=&#34;758&#34; height=&#34;562&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 758px) 100vw, 758px&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Who watches the watchers?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month the Wall Street Journal reported: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wsj.com/articles/hackers-infect-army-of-cameras-dvrs-for-massive-internet-attacks-1475179428&#34;&gt;Hackers Infect Army of Cameras, DVRs for Massive Internet Attacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can something like this happen?  It turns out security cameras and DVRs are just network connected computers, and they can be hacked just like any other computer.  However, it&amp;#8217;s worse than that, a large number of these systems ship with default passwords, so anyone who can connect to them can get into the system and install any software they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-my-firewall&#34;&gt;What about my firewall?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait, what does it matter that there are default passwords on these systems?  These devices are normally behind a firewall, right?  Maybe, but most DVRs and IP cameras are configured so you can view and configure them from outside your firewall.  When these systems are installed, most of them instruct you to set up port forwarding.  This is where you can get into trouble.  If you configure your firewall for port forwarding, you&amp;#8217;re allowing anyone on the internet to connect to your device.  If you setup port forwarding but don&amp;#8217;t bother to change the default passwords, then you&amp;#8217;re asking for trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-are-your-own-it-guy&#34;&gt;You are your own IT guy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do setup port forwarding, make sure you change all the default passwords and keep your firmware up to date.  Yes, this is a hassle.  Updating firmware on wireless security cameras is error prone and confusing.  You have to make sure you have the right firmware for your camera.  Sometimes there are slightly different hardware versions and if you install the wrong firmware on the wrong hardware, you&amp;#8217;ll brick your device.  Another hassle is that most manufacturers insist that you do the upgrade over a wired connection.  This sounds easy until you realize that the camera is mounted somewhere and now you have to get your toolbox and a ladder just to upgrade your firmware.  No wonder these devices are not getting updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-sensr-net-help&#34;&gt;Can Sensr.net help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net: Watch your stuff &#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; doesn&amp;#8217;t require port forwarding (cameras push to our servers, nothing reaches back into your network).  This means if you&amp;#8217;re using security cameras or network attached DVRs don&amp;#8217;t need to be accessible from the internet at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;try-sensr-net-for-free&#34;&gt;Try Sensr.net for free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an IP camera, give us a try.  Sign up for our &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;one week free trial&lt;/a&gt;, no credit card required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stolen Camera Continues Uploading to Sensr.net</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/01/24/stolen-camera-continues-uploading-to-sensr-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 23:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/01/24/stolen-camera-continues-uploading-to-sensr-net/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[&lt;div class=&#34;share_buttons_simple_use_buttons&#34; style=&#34;padding: 10px 0; display: inline-block&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;tweet_button&#34; style=&#34;float: left; vertical-align: top&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/share&#34; class=&#34;twitter-share-button&#34; data-url=&#34;http://ec2-35-161-252-137.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com/2014/01/24/stolen-camera-continues-uploading-to-sensr-net/&#34; data-text=&#34;Stolen Camera Continues Uploading to Sensr.net&#34; data-count=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;facebook_like_button&#34; style=&#34;float: left; vertical-align: top; margin-left: 10px; max-width: 255px&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://flic.kr/p/4TqrbZ&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net we provide a cloud service for recording your webcam or IP camera&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately these cameras sometimes get stolen. Recently we had a user who&amp;#8217;s home was burgalrized and the theif had the gall to steal his Sensr.net connected camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that he also decided to setup the camera for himself, so he took the camera home, after a stop at Taco Bell for some refreshments, and plugged it into his home router. The faithful Foscam jumped on the thief&amp;#8217;s network and continued uploading to Sensr.net. We have some great shots of the thief, along with the remnants of his fast food meal, and even a shot of the bottom of his router.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our user contacted us to see if we could provide the IP address used by the camera while it was uploading to our service. Sure enough, our analytics keeps track of that, so now the police have some pretty good pointers to our bad guy. No news on his capture as of yet, but it&amp;#8217;s pretty gratifying nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net works with pretty much any off the shelf webacam or IP camera.&lt;/a&gt; We simply capture JPEG images uploaded to us via FTP or HTTP. We do motion detection on our side and transform those uploads to live video streams as well as archives. We do a lot more than this, so check out Sensr.net if you&amp;#8217;re interested in learning more. We have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;one week free trial, so give it a try&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Raspberry Pi Security Camera</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/01/19/build-a-raspberry-pi-security-camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 19:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/01/19/build-a-raspberry-pi-security-camera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://www.sudobob.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/2014-01-10-10.21.11.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our friend Bob Coggeshall wrote a nice post on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sudobob.com/raspberry-pi-web-cam-on-sensr-net/&#34;&gt;how to use a webcam and a Raspberry Pi to create a Sensr.net backed security camera&lt;/a&gt;. Who doesn&amp;#8217;t have an old webcam laying around?  Now you can put it to good use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks Bob!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard IP-Cameras Capture Meteor over Siberia</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2013/02/15/dashboard-ip-cameras-capture-meteor-over-siberia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 20:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2013/02/15/dashboard-ip-cameras-capture-meteor-over-siberia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2412&#34; title=&#34;APTOPIX Russia Meteorite&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/02/meteoroverrussia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Russia Meteorite captured by Dashboard Camera on NYTimes&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;338&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/02/meteoroverrussia.jpg 600w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/02/meteoroverrussia-300x169.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dozens of videos of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/16/world/europe/meteorite-fragments-are-said-to-rain-down-on-siberia.html?pagewanted=2&amp;hp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;meteor over Siberia&lt;/a&gt; just a few hours ago are popping up on YouTube, almost all captured from &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dashboard IP-Cameras&lt;/a&gt;, extremely prevalent in Russia. The footage is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using our new Sensr.net app, Sensr VCam, you can use your iOS devices to easily act as a dashboard IP-Camera, streaming H.264 video to the Sensr.net cloud. Once in the cloud, your video feed can be viewed live on the device, or viewed later from the Sensr.net archive. We&amp;#8217;ve also made it easy to share video clips on YouTube with your friend, family, or the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren&amp;#8217;t already a Sensr.net member, sign up for a free 7 day trial and get started using your iOS device as an on-the-go surveillance solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Want to write your own IP-Camera based app? Use our open &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/api&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sensr.net IP-Camera API &amp;amp; SDK &lt;/a&gt;to create whatever you can dream up._&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Terms of service here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/apiterms&#34;&gt;terms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>