<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sensr.net Blog | Watch your Stuff!</title>
    <link>http://blog.sensr.net/categories/iphone/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sensr.net Blog | Watch your Stuff!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.sensr.net/categories/iphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aelec Bluetooth Headphones for iPhone</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/aelec-bluetooth-headphones-for-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 13:04:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/aelec-bluetooth-headphones-for-iphone/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Since Apple decided to drop the headphone jack on their latest phones, I thought I would try out some bluetooth headphones. Amazon suggested
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/blah&#34;&gt;aelec 5030&lt;/a&gt;. These have a built in battery and I liked that the earbuds are connected to eachother (left
and right) by a wire so they won&amp;rsquo;t be too easy to loose. I imagined jogging or working out without having to worry about a cord connecting my
ears to the phone. I hate doing abs and having to have the phone in my pocket. Jogging isn&amp;rsquo;t so bad with regular headphones, but the swinging
wire can be a pain. On the treadmill it can be downright dangerous. More than once my arms have hit the headphone wire and yanked my phone off
the treadmill controls and onto the belt where I nearly tripped on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of earbud headphones. I like that I can just stuff them in my ear and the little rubber covers block out sound on their own. The
aelec headphones come with a bunch of different size rubbery buds. The headphones also have acttive noise reduction, but I can&amp;rsquo;t actually
tell if this is doing anything. You can&amp;rsquo;t turn it on or off, it&amp;rsquo;s always on, so it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to tell if it&amp;rsquo;s working.  That being
said, I&amp;rsquo;m on a plane right now listening to Pandora and it sounds pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a test, I just switched to my cheap wired headeset, I&amp;rsquo;m still on the plane. I&amp;rsquo;m sorry to say that the wired headphones sound much better
than the aelec headphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;poor-sound-quality&#34;&gt;Poor sound quality&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say I was pretty dissappointed when I first heard these headphones. There isn&amp;rsquo;t much bass at all.  I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge fan of bass,
but even I am unsatisfied with the sounds of these guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;neat-features&#34;&gt;Neat Features&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can get over the poor quality sound, the headphones seem to work very well with iOS. All the control buttons are on the right earbud.
Press and hold to turn on or off. There are buttons for up and down volume. The power button also does pause play as well as forward and
reverse. There is a small LED light that lets you know the headphones are on and connected. There is also some audio feedback. A voice will
tell you that the headphones are connected or powering on. It seems to be speaking Chinese though. I heard it in English the first time I
turned on the headphones, but lately it&amp;rsquo;s been speaking something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;charging-and-battery-life&#34;&gt;Charging and battery life&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It comes with a little micro USB cable so you can charge the battery. The slot is well hidden in the right ear bud. It seems to be hidden and
well located as to avoid getting wet in the rain.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t run out of batter yet and I&amp;rsquo;ve used the headphones for a few hours.  I was wondering if there was some way to find out the battery level.  It turns out my iPhone displays a little battery meter next to the
Bluetooth icon on the phone screen.  See the image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/iphone-aelec.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;neck-slide&#34;&gt;Neck slide&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you wear these you have to decide if the cord goes in front of your neck or behind.  Behind makes the most sense to me. If
the wire is behind your neck, then you can easily puck out one or both of the buds and let them just dangle around your neck.  If
the wire was in front and you removed one earbud, then the entire contraption would be hanging from one earbud, which might not
last very long. Of coure you can&amp;rsquo;t pluck out both earbuds with this configuration since it would just fall to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do find that when I jog, the loose wire tends to work it&amp;rsquo;s way over to my right side and even starts pulling out the left
ear bud.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why this happens but it&amp;rsquo;s actually quite annoying. I wonder if it means that I&amp;rsquo;m lopsided somehow.
 Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll just have to try putting the wire in front and see if that solves the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;worth-it&#34;&gt;Worth it?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got these for $25 on Amazon and at that price I would say yes, it&amp;rsquo;s worth it.  I&amp;rsquo;m disappointed that the sound quality is so
poor, even compared with my $5 headphones from TJ Maxx.  I might try returning these and trying again when I upgrade to an iPhone 7.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>