<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on Sensr.net Blog | Watch your Stuff!</title>
    <link>http://blog.sensr.net/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on Sensr.net Blog | Watch your Stuff!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 10:13:53 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.sensr.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfa R36 AWUS036NH Network Scan Not Working</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/12/alfa-r36-awus036nh-network-scan-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 10:13:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/12/alfa-r36-awus036nh-network-scan-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfa.com.tw/download_show.php?combo_0=11&amp;amp;combo_1=R36&amp;amp;combo_2=Firmware&amp;amp;k&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/R36FirmwareVersions.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;R36 Firmware Versions&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you having problems with your Alfa R36 not being able to scan for networks?  If the firmware version on your R36 needs
to be at least 1.2.1.2 or it won&amp;rsquo;t work with the AWUS036NH.  See the screen shot above. At first I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that I had
a different version of the AWUS036NH, the version that has an H at the end: AWUS036NH not AWUS036N.  They are different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the firmware upgrade everything works great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfa.com.tw/download_show.php?combo_0=11&amp;amp;combo_1=R36&amp;amp;combo_2=Firmware&amp;amp;k&#34;&gt;firmware here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-this-for&#34;&gt;What is this for?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/AlfaDevices.jpg&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;R36 and AWUS036NH&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;R36 and AWUS036NH&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use the R36 and the AWUS036NH to create your own hotspot out of another wifi network. The AWUS036NH is essentially an antennae.
The R36 is a router that also creates it&amp;rsquo;s own wifi network. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a bunch of devices in your RV or boat.  You can connect
them all to the R36&amp;rsquo;s wifi network.  Then when you park in the Starbucks parking lot, you can tell the R36 to use the Starbucks wifi
and all of your devices on your local network will connect to the world on over the Starbucks network.  You could have security cameras
and laptops and wireless printers all connected to your R36.  Thus you&amp;rsquo;ll have to &lt;em&gt;scan for networks&lt;/em&gt; whenever you change locations, but
at least you won&amp;rsquo;t need to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have yours working, you might want to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.rokland.com/blogs/news/6547671-how-to-optimize-your-alfa-r36-router&#34;&gt;this article on optimizing your R36&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FTP Setup on the Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/ftp-setup-on-the-foscam-wireless-security-camera-1920tvl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 11:36:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/ftp-setup-on-the-foscam-wireless-security-camera-1920tvl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/foscamr2.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
 --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:25%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/foscamr2.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;width:60%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamBox.jpg&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Foscam-Wireless-Security-Camera-1920TVL/dp/B01DJ1FTTS/sensr-20&#34;&gt;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&lt;/a&gt; is the
latest slim model from Foscam, also called the R2 it seems. I just opened this one yesterday and Foscam seems to be upping their game.
The box is much nicer than they used in the previous models. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit more like the Apple experience. Not bad for a $70 product!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;it-speaks&#34;&gt;It speaks!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera is easy to setup using the Foscam app.  As a nice bonus they have added audio cues that come from the camera.  It says &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Hello Foscam&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; when it powers up. Its little head rotates around and the camera said &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ethernet connection succeeded&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.  Later
after I setup the wifi, it said &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wireless connection succeeded&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.  I have to admit this is a nice feature. No more wondering if the
camera connected to the network or not.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I want the audio piping up when the power goes off and back on though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;interesting-features-in-the-foscam-app&#34;&gt;Interesting Features in the Foscam App&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/foscam/id924381688?mt=8&#34;&gt;Foscam app&lt;/a&gt; mostly seems to work. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s filled with grammatical mistakes.
It let&amp;rsquo;s you share the images on &lt;strong&gt;WeChat&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;WeChat Moments&lt;/strong&gt;, whatever that is. (Ok, it&amp;rsquo;s the Facebook &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wechat.com/en/&#34;&gt;Messenger of
China&lt;/a&gt;, but not really very important to the non-Chinese market.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:30%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamAmerica.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Country selection Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;width:30%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamWechat.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wechat Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;width:30%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamFirmware.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Firware upgrade Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a selection for United States but you can select &lt;em&gt;America&lt;/em&gt; which is kind of cute.  I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure they mean France
not French, but maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a language selector as well as a location selector?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe the best new feature is that you can upgrade the firmware in the app! Excellent! Now when there is a security issue in the firmware, the
app will make it simple to perform the upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-s-missing&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s missing?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has a lot of controls but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the local IP address for the camera. If you&amp;rsquo;re going to setup this camera for FTP you&amp;rsquo;ll need to
find it&amp;rsquo;s IP address. Normally I would recommend connecting to your router and looking for the device with a matching MAC address. This will
work if you&amp;rsquo;re using the wired connection. The MAC address is printed on the bottom of the camera. However, the wireless MAC address is not.
It would be nice if the app would tell you the URL to connect to the web interface. If you&amp;rsquo;ve already put your amera on wifi, you can still
find it but you may have to try connecting to a bunch of different IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;port-88&#34;&gt;Port 88!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to connect to the camera, make sure to use port 88. For some reason the default port for Foscam is 88. That means you&amp;rsquo;ll have
to go to &lt;code&gt;http://IP:88/&lt;/code&gt; to get to the web interface. For example, if your camera&amp;rsquo;s IP is &lt;code&gt;172.16.20.73&lt;/code&gt; you&amp;rsquo;ll need to go to
&lt;code&gt;http://172.16.20.73:88/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;safari-plugins&#34;&gt;Safari Plugins!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using a Mac, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install plugins.  I really wish these camera manufacturers would just use web standards instead
of making us install software.  I tried configuring the camera without the plugins, but it really seems to enforce this.  Maybe future
versions of the app will support FTP configuration so we can skip the browser all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;configure-the-ftp-server&#34;&gt;Configure the FTP Server&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Log on to your account at &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; and click the add camera button. This will give you the three pieces of information
you need to configure your camera: server, username, and password. Our server names are &lt;code&gt;f0.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt; through &lt;code&gt;f9.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt;. The usernames
are &lt;code&gt;camNNN&lt;/code&gt; where &lt;code&gt;NNN&lt;/code&gt; is an integer. The password is generated randomly. Be careful since in a password some characters can be confused.
Zeros and Os looks alike. Ones and Ls also look alike. It&amp;rsquo;s best to copy and paste the passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have these, you can then go to the FTP sever page on the camera, which looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamFTPSettings.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FTP server URL shows a dir at the end. On the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; side we just ignore this. You can add it if you wish but it&amp;rsquo;s
not needed. Your URL should start with FTP though, like this: &lt;code&gt;ftp://fX.sensr.net/&lt;/code&gt;, where X is the server that
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; tells you to use for your camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;configure-snapshot-settings&#34;&gt;Configure Snapshot Settings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you&amp;rsquo;ll want to configure the snapshot settings, which tells the camera to upload JPEG snapshots to &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;. We
recommend you send an image per second to our servers. (See &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/10/24/ip-camera-no-firewall-config/&#34;&gt;No Firewall Config&lt;/a&gt; for more details
on why we recommend this.) This way we can generate a live Motion JPEG stream (MJPEG) on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; site. Make sure to
select all in the upper left hand corner of the schedule so the camera will always upload. If you don&amp;rsquo;t want us to process images on certain
days or certain hours, this is the place to configure that. Make sure to click the Save button at the top. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve done this your Foscam
should start uploading to &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamSnapshotSettings.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; side the page should go from this:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-s3.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt; Waiting for upload&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To a page that shows the image your camera uploaded.  Something like this:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-success.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Success!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, now you&amp;rsquo;re done with the camera config. Your camera is now on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ll archive all the motion
events, giving you 30 days of archives, SMS and email alerts, guest access, and a whole lot more.  You can view the live stream on our website
or in our apps. No firewall configuration is needed. No PC in the basement required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any problems, send email to info @ sensr.net and we&amp;rsquo;ll try to help you out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;don-t-set-scheduled-recording&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Set Scheduled Recording&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be tempted to set the Scheduled Recording.  This is for MKV video files.  If you upload those to Sensr.net we&amp;rsquo;ll just remove
them, since we only support JPEG files right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/UnsetFoscamScheduledRecording.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;don-t-set-motion-detection-settings&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Set Motion Detection Settings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also don&amp;rsquo;t need the motion detection settings to work with Sensr.net.  We do the motion detection on the server side.
See our blog post &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2011/07/25/true-meaning-of-motion-detection-off/&#34;&gt;The True Meaning of Motion Detection Off&lt;/a&gt;
for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamMotionDetectionSettings.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;shodan-fun&#34;&gt;Shodan Fun&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The built in web server seems to be lighttpd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the headers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTTP/1.1 200 OK
Content-Type: text/html
Accept-Ranges: bytes
ETag: &amp;quot;18210424&amp;quot;
Last-Modified: Thu, 28 Jul 2016 03:47:34 GMT
Content-Length: 38561
Date: Thu, 01 Dec 2016 12:08:20 GMT
Server: lighttpd/1.4.31
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scan on shodan.io for the etag &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shodan.io/search?query=ETag%3A+%2218210424%22&#34;&gt;finds a few cameras&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hikvision FTP Server IP address leads to Zombie Apocalypse</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/hikvision-ftp-server-ip-address-leads-to-zombie-apocalypse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 21:59:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/hikvision-ftp-server-ip-address-leads-to-zombie-apocalypse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/zombie-ip-camera.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Never give up!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Ok, these &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Hikvision-DS-2CD2042WD-I-Network-English-Security/dp/B01DIKF4XG/sensr-20&#34;&gt;Hikvision cameras&lt;/a&gt; are pretty nice
and seem like great quality for the price.  However, I have one major issue with them, they
don&amp;rsquo;t let you use hostnames for the FTP server.  You have to use an IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Hikvision-DS-2CD2042WD-I-Network-English-Security/dp/B01DIKF4XG/sensr-20&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/DS-2CD2042WD-I.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Hikvision DS-2CD2042WD-I Bullet Camera&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/hikvision-ftp-setup.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Hikvision FTP Setup&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Why would they require this?  I suppose for most cameras connect to a server on the local network, thus it won&amp;rsquo;t have a DNS name
anyway, why not just require an IP address? It means that when the camera does connect to the FTP server, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to do
a DNS lookup, but that seems like a pretty big trade off. You have to hardwire the IP address into the camera config.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-external-servers&#34;&gt;What about external servers?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you require an IP address, then you need to find the IP address of the server. At &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; we run FTP servers and we
use hostnames like &lt;code&gt;f0.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt;. If you want to use the Hikvision with our service, you need to connect to one of our servers (currently f0 through f9).
But to use the Hikvision, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to find out the IP address of our servers.  In the case of &lt;code&gt;f9.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt; you can run &lt;code&gt;nslookup&lt;/code&gt; like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ nslookup f9.sensr.net
Server:		8.8.8.8
Address:	8.8.8.8#53

Non-authoritative answer:
Name:	f9.sensr.net
Address: 74.207.245.42
Name:	f9.sensr.net
Address: 96.126.101.33
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, notice that it returns two different answers.  At Sensr.net we (currently) have two servers that serve as &lt;code&gt;f9.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt;.  We do this
for redundancy.  If one of our servers fails, then the other one can take over for it.  Of course this redundancy won&amp;rsquo;t help you
if you hard wire the IP address.  For the Hikvision, just pick one or the other IP addresses and it should work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-loadbalancing-and-failover&#34;&gt;What about loadbalancing and failover?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of screws up our load balancing and failover.  But at least it works.  However, it only works as long as our servers keep the same IP
address.  What if we upgrade or move a server?  It&amp;rsquo;s IP address will change and your camera won&amp;rsquo;t work anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maybe-security-could-be-compromised-too&#34;&gt;Maybe security could be compromised too&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use servers at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linode.com&#34;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; and we might decide to upgrade and get a bigger server at Linode,
or maybe move to &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt; or even &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Cloud&lt;/a&gt;. In that case,
the IP address that we used to use will get deprecated.  This probably means your camera will stop working.  But it could mean that it starts
uploading to a server that isn&amp;rsquo;t part of Sensr.net!  Let&amp;rsquo;s say we drop the server at Linode, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty likely that Linode will re-use that IP
address for someone else.  That new owner might notice that there are cameras trying to connect to it.  That new owner might also decide to let
those cameras connect and then they could start collecting images that are uploaded by your cameras.  Hmm, that seems like a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-serious-is-this&#34;&gt;How serious is this?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we have changed the IP addresses of our upload servers once in 6 years.  So it doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen often.  However, we are working on a
major change and I expect the IP addresses will change in the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-can-we-do-to-help&#34;&gt;What can we do to help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we change servers and drop the IP addresses for these machines,
we can move over the DNS names (&lt;code&gt;f0.sensr.net .. f9.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt;) and see what cameras continue to connect. If all the cameras move over (they won&amp;rsquo;t)
then we don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be cameras left connecting to the old IP addresses.  In this case we can warn our users that they need
to update their cameras.  We&amp;rsquo;ll probably send out an email and give our users some time to make the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;zombie-cameras&#34;&gt;Zombie cameras&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/zombiecam.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Never give up!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We have quite a few zombie cameras trying to connect to our servers.  Zombies are cameras that used to work with the service, but no longer
are on paid accounts.  This means we don&amp;rsquo;t let them upload images, their logins fail.  But most zombies keep plugging away,  mindlessly attempting
to upload to our servers even though we won&amp;rsquo;t let them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of these cameras, we may not be able to contact the owners, so after we finally decomission the servers, they may end up connecting to
some new server deployed at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linode.com&#34;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt;. If the owner of that new server decides to let the zombie connect, they could end up collecting
lots of potentially private images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iot-gone-mad&#34;&gt;IoT gone mad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one example of how the IoT world is leading to unintended consequences.  People setup cameras so they can be more secure, but
through a sequence of perfectly normal events they end up with something they don&amp;rsquo;t expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll ask Linode if they will decommission those IP addresses.  Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll just keep paying for them.  One thing is for sure, we will
warn users before we release the IP addresses back into the pool.  We&amp;rsquo;ll keep track of how much upload traffic we get to our deprecated
servers.  It might lead to another interesting blog post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned, the Zombie Apocalypse is far from over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shameless-plug&#34;&gt;Shameless plug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re still not afraid of the zombies, we would love to have you as a customer. &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;Point your IP camera at us&lt;/a&gt; and we&amp;rsquo;ll do some useful stuff with what you send us. We have a free trial, so it won&amp;rsquo;t cost you anything.  If you decide not to stick with us, please
delete our FTP server from your camera. It will be as satisfying as shooting a zombie in the head!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why no open source IoT Firmware?</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/why-no-open-source-iot-firmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 20:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/why-no-open-source-iot-firmware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Dans les entrailles urbaines / In the urban bowels&#34; href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/m43photos/12239139316/in/photolist-jDwMHo-cxs18J-fAiNqu-dgqBrp-8JiYae-zJCUs-5hmBet-ciyJEf-aqSgjf-4zhcab-e6MK4D-3dqLhP-qP2FY-9u9Vmd-aqrFT2-6F34w2-5NAo8e-5M2nnt-cxt85q-2zrJy9-7aUP9A-5NEEK7-deB66G-bEtv1q-dksYJC-c7gy4E-rU8r9v-5S8j7P-bToeAP-6F7cKq-5NEEMf-6F7d5b-dNifDu-3bsbWr-6F7cUA-5NAoan-5NEEfh-ckh731-5NAod6-sNL1k-8DkNxR-skKu3-sGNzi-8B9Dfe-4Poqgd-cv5hA5-cvgpHu-iH8cKJ-jSg8jZ-dgSE9g&#34; data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5524/12239139316_6e97104ce8_k.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dans les entrailles urbaines / In the urban bowels&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;334&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IoT (Internet of Things) is taking off. We&amp;rsquo;re coming up with all kinds of internet connected devices. Many of these devices are simply computers with interesting sensors and controllers attached. At Sensr.net we think mostly about IP cameras, which are a specific kind of IoT device. But that &lt;a href=&#34;https://nest.com/thermostat/meet-nest-thermostat/&#34; title=&#34;Nest Thermostat&#34;&gt;Nest thermostat&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Echo-Bluetooth-Speaker-with-WiFi-Alexa/dp/B00X4WHP5E&#34; title=&#34;Amazon Echo&#34;&gt;Amazon Echo speaker&lt;/a&gt; are also examples of IoT devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days most IP cameras will connect to your internet via WiFi or Ethernet and allow you to view and control the camera remotely. Many of these cameras include a P2P (peer to peer) feature that allows you to view the camera directly even if you don&amp;rsquo;t open your firewall. This is a neat trick which is accomplished by having the camera keep open a connection back to some well known server. When you want to connect to your camera, you&amp;rsquo;re really connecting to some remote server (in China maybe?) that then does some network magic (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/STUN&#34; title=&#34;STUN: Session Traversal Utilities for NAT&#34;&gt;STUN&lt;/a&gt;) and lets your smartphone app connect to your camera through your firewall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That nice P2P feature is pretty great, but it also means that there are servers out there on the net that can get inside your home network. Where are those servers running? Who&amp;rsquo;s job is it to make sure they are secure? Who has access to those servers and thus your network and even your cameras?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-your-cams-are-belong-to-us&#34;&gt;All your cams are belong to us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Mostly we&amp;rsquo;re pretty cavalier about connecting cool new gadgets to our networks. Maybe we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be. It seems like there ought to be some way to make sure the devices you trust are actually trustworthy. How can we be sure that our security cameras are actually secure? (Warning: &lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2016/10/19/is-your-security-camera-hacking-someone-else/&#34; title=&#34;Cameras hacked into botnets&#34;&gt;They probably aren&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truthiness-in-our-firmware&#34;&gt;Truthiness in our firmware?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these devices run an operating system of some kind embedded down in their firmware. What if we created an open source firmware that we could trust? We could buy fun cheap hardware from our friends in China but then install our own good old open source code on that hardware instead of trusting the glop that came on it. Don&amp;rsquo;t want your camera connecting out some potentially compromised P2P jumphost somewhere? No problem! Just install your own firmware and configure your own jumphost or maybe one run by a company you trust. (This could be a new business opportunity for &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net: Watch your stuff!&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; maybe&amp;#8230;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-say-tomato-6-8230&#34;&gt;You say &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tomato_(firmware)&#34; title=&#34;Tomato Firmware&#34;&gt;tomato&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one successful example of this, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dd-wrt.com/site/index&#34; title=&#34;DD-WRT Site&#34;&gt;DD-WRT software&lt;/a&gt; that runs on a large number of routers.  There are a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_router_firmware_projects&#34; title=&#34;Router Firmware&#34;&gt;open source firmwares&lt;/a&gt; out there. Why can&amp;rsquo;t we have one for cameras? Or more generally IoT devices?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-together-now&#34;&gt;All together now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in joining an effort along these lines, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@sensr.net?Subject=Open%20firmware&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;drop me an email&lt;/a&gt; or contribute to the project on Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sensrnet/sensros&#34; title=&#34;SensrOS: Open source IP Camera Firmware&#34;&gt;https://github.com/sensrnet/sensros&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of cool things that could be built into this firmware.  Imagine the machine learning projects or advanced image recognition that could be built into something like this. More basic things could be done too, like reference designs for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onvif.org/&#34; title=&#34;ONVIF&#34;&gt;ONVIF&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psialliance.org/&#34; title=&#34;Physical Security Interoperability Alliance&#34;&gt;PSIA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is your security camera hacking someone else?</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/is-your-security-camera-hacking-someone-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 18:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/is-your-security-camera-hacking-someone-else/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3207&#34; style=&#34;width: 768px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3207&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2016/10/wsjscreenshot-1024x5741.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Who watches the watchers?&#34; width=&#34;758&#34; height=&#34;562&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 758px) 100vw, 758px&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Who watches the watchers?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month the Wall Street Journal reported: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wsj.com/articles/hackers-infect-army-of-cameras-dvrs-for-massive-internet-attacks-1475179428&#34;&gt;Hackers Infect Army of Cameras, DVRs for Massive Internet Attacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can something like this happen?  It turns out security cameras and DVRs are just network connected computers, and they can be hacked just like any other computer.  However, it&amp;#8217;s worse than that, a large number of these systems ship with default passwords, so anyone who can connect to them can get into the system and install any software they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-my-firewall&#34;&gt;What about my firewall?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait, what does it matter that there are default passwords on these systems?  These devices are normally behind a firewall, right?  Maybe, but most DVRs and IP cameras are configured so you can view and configure them from outside your firewall.  When these systems are installed, most of them instruct you to set up port forwarding.  This is where you can get into trouble.  If you configure your firewall for port forwarding, you&amp;#8217;re allowing anyone on the internet to connect to your device.  If you setup port forwarding but don&amp;#8217;t bother to change the default passwords, then you&amp;#8217;re asking for trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-are-your-own-it-guy&#34;&gt;You are your own IT guy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do setup port forwarding, make sure you change all the default passwords and keep your firmware up to date.  Yes, this is a hassle.  Updating firmware on wireless security cameras is error prone and confusing.  You have to make sure you have the right firmware for your camera.  Sometimes there are slightly different hardware versions and if you install the wrong firmware on the wrong hardware, you&amp;#8217;ll brick your device.  Another hassle is that most manufacturers insist that you do the upgrade over a wired connection.  This sounds easy until you realize that the camera is mounted somewhere and now you have to get your toolbox and a ladder just to upgrade your firmware.  No wonder these devices are not getting updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-sensr-net-help&#34;&gt;Can Sensr.net help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net: Watch your stuff &#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; doesn&amp;#8217;t require port forwarding (cameras push to our servers, nothing reaches back into your network).  This means if you&amp;#8217;re using security cameras or network attached DVRs don&amp;#8217;t need to be accessible from the internet at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;try-sensr-net-for-free&#34;&gt;Try Sensr.net for free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an IP camera, give us a try.  Sign up for our &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;one week free trial&lt;/a&gt;, no credit card required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legally Monitor your Airbnb with cheap Sensr.net security cameras</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/09/27/legally-monitor-your-airbnb-with-cheap-sensr-net-security-cameras/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 01:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/09/27/legally-monitor-your-airbnb-with-cheap-sensr-net-security-cameras/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been renting our place on &lt;a title=&#34;Airbnb&#34; href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; for about a year now and it&amp;rsquo;s been great to have &lt;a title=&#34;Sensr.net&#34; href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; cameras monitoring our place while we aren&amp;rsquo;t there. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, we don&amp;rsquo;t have cameras &lt;em&gt;inside the private spaces of our home&lt;/em&gt;, we have exterior cameras that monitor the approaches to the house. Think &lt;strong&gt;Driveway Camera&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Front Door Camera,&lt;/strong&gt; etc. We only monitor the &lt;em&gt;public spaces&lt;/em&gt; around our home, with &lt;em&gt;one exception&lt;/em&gt;: owner only spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;don-t-go-there&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Go There&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we rent our home on Airbnb we close off a handful of rooms, like the home office, garage, and basement storage rooms. We &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; have cameras in these spaces, where we &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t allow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; the Airbnb guest to go. These cameras are behind locked doors and should never record the guests unless they have picked the locks to get into the rooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;party-zone&#34;&gt;Party Zone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External cameras are great in letting you know when or if the guest arrived and if the correct number of guests arrived. Our home has a strict &amp;#8216;no parties&amp;rsquo; rule. We have found this violated a couple of times and it was obvious from the cameras that more than the max 8 guests were staying at the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;neighbor-friendly&#34;&gt;Neighbor Friendly&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We share a driveway with our neighbors, and we make it very clear to our Airbnb guests that they are not to use the driveway.  This didn&amp;rsquo;t really work the first few times, but after we added &lt;em&gt;You will be fined for using the driveway&lt;/em&gt; to the directions with an additional &lt;em&gt;The driveway is monitor by security cameras&lt;/em&gt; this problem went away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;external-cameras&#34;&gt;External Cameras&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding external cameras can be more difficult than adding an internal wifi camera.  There are lots of great solutions, and if you can run a wire to the location where you want the camera, a POE (Power Over Ethernet) camera can be a great solution.  You only need to run one wire but you need a special router that can also send power.  If you live in a temperate climate, you might try &lt;a title=&#34;HOWTO Make a Cheap Network Camera Enclosure&#34; href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2011/05/26/howto-make-cheap-network-camera-enclosure/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this cheap camera cover solution&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;internal-cameras&#34;&gt;Internal Cameras&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internal cameras are pretty easy to setup and there are thousands of models to choose from.  Generally these are cheap and work with your wifi.  You only need a power outlet and access to your wifi.  Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a title=&#34;How to Setup the TENVIS IPROBOT3 with Cloud recording&#34; href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2014/07/03/how-to-setup-the-tenvis-iprobot3-with-cloud-recording/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tenvis&lt;/a&gt; PTZ (pan, tilt, zoom) cameras.  I use their live viewing app to view the camera and change it&amp;rsquo;s positioning.  I use Sensr.net for recording, alerts, and sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;share-the-fun&#34;&gt;Share the Fun&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a friend who keeps an eye on our home when we aren&amp;rsquo;t around.  With Sensr.net it&amp;rsquo;s easy to give him access to the exterior cameras.  When you have a camera on Sensr.net, you can give other&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a title=&#34;Guest Access for Sensr.net Cameras&#34; href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2012/04/11/guest-access-for-sensr-net-cameras/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;guest access to those cameras&lt;/a&gt;.  He helps out when we&amp;rsquo;re not around and manages the cleaning crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cost-effective&#34;&gt;Cost Effective&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Sensr.net you can use almost any camera.  If your camera can upload JPEG images with FTP (like 98% of all security cameras), then it will work with Sensr.net.  We don&amp;rsquo;t sell cameras, so we&amp;rsquo;re _camera agnostic.  _You could even make your own camera with a Raspberry Pi and a USB cam and it would work with Sensr.net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-notified&#34;&gt;Get Notified&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Sensr.net not only do we record in the cloud, but we can send you alerts when we detect motion.  This works great for the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;owner only&lt;/em&gt; spaces.&lt;/strong&gt;  If you have a camera setup in your private space, you&amp;rsquo;ll appreciate a SMS or email when something starts moving around in there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;free-trial&#34;&gt;Free Trial!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re an Airbnb host, you can give this a try for free.  If you&amp;rsquo;re not an Airbnb host, you can try it out too!  We have a one week free trial.  Grab a camera and give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warning: setting up an IP camera can be a bit complex.  If you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable setting up a wifi router, then you&amp;rsquo;ll probably be fine.  One big advantage to using Sensr.net is that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do any &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/10/24/ip-camera-no-firewall-config/&#34; title=&#34;View IP Camera Remotely, No Firewall Config&#34;&gt;port forwarding or complex firewall rules&lt;/a&gt;, so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit easier than you might expect if you&amp;rsquo;ve tried this kind of thing in the past.  If you get stuck, just drop us an email at support@sensr.net and we&amp;rsquo;ll give you a hand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensr.net Security Camera Offline</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/02/29/security-camera-offline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 13:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/02/29/security-camera-offline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sensr.net shows cameras as offline if they haven&amp;rsquo;t uploaded an image in the last 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does this happen? We recommend that you have your camera upload images continuously to Sensr.net at 1 or 2 snapshots per second. This way you can view the live stream on our site &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/10/24/ip-camera-no-firewall-config/&#34; title=&#34;View IP Camera Remotely, No Firewall Config&#34;&gt;without opening your firewall&lt;/a&gt;. If you have your camera set to only upload images on motion, then when there is no motion, we&amp;rsquo;ll show your camera as offline.  See this post about &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2011/07/25/true-meaning-of-motion-detection-off/&#34; title=&#34;True meaning of motion detection off&#34;&gt;configuring cameras with motion detection&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Camera Archiving and Clip Download</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/02/28/security-camera-archiving-and-clip-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 13:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/02/28/security-camera-archiving-and-clip-download/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With your Sensr.net account,  we save images for one month on our site. Images are deleted when they are 32 days old. If you want to keep the images longer just save them as favorites or make a clip. Favorites and clips are kept until you delete the camera from our service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2014/04/29/making-clips-on-sensr-net/&#34; title=&#34;Making Clips on Sensr.net&#34;&gt;make a clip&lt;/a&gt;, we will generate an mpeg file and send you a link to download it. The link we send is good for 30 days.  Make sure your login email is correct and check your spam folder if you don&amp;rsquo;t see the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re working on some programs that will allow you to pull down images to your local hard drive. See the open source project here.  If you&amp;rsquo;re a coder, give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adamb/Sensr-utils&#34; title=&#34;Sensr Utils&#34;&gt;https://github.com/adamb/Sensr-utils&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensr.net Revenue Experiment</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2015/04/04/sensr-net-revenue-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 20:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2015/04/04/sensr-net-revenue-experiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3158&#34; style=&#34;width: 650px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;size-large wp-image-3158&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2015/04/Screenshot-2015-04-04-12.56.41-1024x488.png&#34; alt=&#34;Look at growth from new users versus growth from existing users.&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;305&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2015/04/Screenshot-2015-04-04-12.56.41-1024x488.png 1024w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2015/04/Screenshot-2015-04-04-12.56.41-300x143.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Look at growth from new users versus growth from existing users.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Sensr.net we use &lt;a href=&#34;https://stripe.com&#34; title=&#34;Stripe&#34;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt; to handle all the credit card charges. Recently I started using &lt;a href=&#34;http://home.profitwell.com/&#34; title=&#34;ProfitWell, a free tool for SaaS metrics&#34;&gt;Profitwell, a free tool for SaaS metrics&lt;/a&gt;, to try to understand better where we are making money and where we are losing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of our growth today comes from new users. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if we could convince existing users to spend more? For us, that means users with an existing camera might be enticed to add another camera. After all, if you&amp;rsquo;re paying $9.95 for one camera, adding a second for only $4.95 should seem attractive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to try an incentive. I looked for all users who have a single camera on the site, are in good standing, and have logged in recently. That turned out to be 138 users. This morning I sent them &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/?u=180d5f24fadceaa24de070d6f&amp;amp;id=8a5f29a15e&#34; title=&#34;April Sensr.net Offer&#34;&gt;an offer that I hope they can&amp;rsquo;t refuse&lt;/a&gt;. If they add a second camera by April 26th, I&amp;rsquo;ll give them a credit of $14.90, or one month&amp;rsquo;s service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea if this will work or not, but I&amp;rsquo;ll report back and we&amp;rsquo;ll see!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, I used &lt;a title=&#34;Mail Chimp&#34; href=&#34;http://mailchimp.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mail Chimp&lt;/a&gt; to do the email campaign.  The most difficult part of this was building the SQL query to gather the emails.    Now that I have that, I may try to integrate an ongoing campaign using &lt;a href=&#34;http://customer.io/&#34; title=&#34;Targeted Human Emails&#34;&gt;Customer.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say that this experiment is also inspired by the book &lt;a title=&#34;Predictably Irrational&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Predictably-Irrational-Revised-Expanded-Decisions-ebook/dp/B002C949KE/sensr-20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Predictably Irrational&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a title=&#34;Dan Ariely&#34; href=&#34;http://danariely.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dan Ariely&lt;/a&gt;.  Reading about how people make decisions is pretty interesting!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensr.net Bitcoin Experiment</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/12/26/sensr-net-bitcoin-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 16:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/12/26/sensr-net-bitcoin-experiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a user ask to pay his Sensr.net bill in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Main_Page&#34; title=&#34;Bitcoin Wiki&#34;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;. We use Stripe to process payments and &lt;a href=&#34;https://stripe.com/bitcoin&#34; title=&#34;Stripe and Bitcoin&#34;&gt;they don&amp;rsquo;t yet support Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;. However a friend recommended Coinbase, so I set up a merchant page there where you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coinbase.com/sensr&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net Bitcoin Page&#34;&gt;pay Sensr.net in Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in paying your Sensr.net bill using Bitcoin, just let us know. If you already have a Sensr.net account, just pay us in Bitcoin and we&amp;rsquo;ll add the credit to your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions on this, just drop us an email to billing at Sensr.net.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Como Configurar a Gravação da D-Link DCS-5010L com FTP</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/10/03/como-configurar-a-gravacao-da-d-link-dcs-5010l-com-ftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 16:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/10/03/como-configurar-a-gravacao-da-d-link-dcs-5010l-com-ftp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3076&#34; style=&#34;width: 386px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/uploads/2014/09/DCS-5010L-BR.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-3076 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-5010L-BR.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;D-Link 5010L&#34; width=&#34;376&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-5010L-BR.jpg 376w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-5010L-BR-250x300.jpg 250w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 376px) 100vw, 376px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    D-Link 5010L
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A câmera &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.dlink.com/products/home-solutions/pan-tilt-daynight-network-camera-2/&#34; title=&#34;DCS 5010L&#34;&gt;D-Link DCS 5010L&lt;/a&gt; é um dos modelos mais populares da D-Link com visão noturna, rotação horizontal e vertical, WiFi e funciona com o serviço MyDlink. O valor da DCS-5010L é também muito acessível: atualmente ela &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/webhp?sourceid=chrome-instant&amp;amp;ion=1&amp;amp;espv=2&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8#q=dlink+brasil+DCS-5010L&amp;amp;start=10&#34; title=&#34;DCS-5010L na Amazon&#34;&gt;custa $75 na Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. Esta câmera é muito parecida com a DCS-5020L, mas custa quase metade do preço.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Necessidade de Gravação&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apesar do serviço &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mydlink.com/entrance&#34; title=&#34;Site MyDlink&#34;&gt;MyDlink&lt;/a&gt; permitir que você veja essa câmera remotamente, ele não suporta nenhum tipo de gravação ou armazenamento de imagens. É aqui que o Sensr.net entra. Nosso serviço permite armazenar automaticamente as imagens captadas no último mês. Este artigo vai ajudar você a configurar sua câmera DCS-5010L para que você veja tudo o que se passa com as suas coisas enquanto você não está olhando!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Também vou mostrar como configurar a câmera para enviar imagens para o site do &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;, para que você tire partido de todas as funcionalidades do nosso serviço, como o armazenamento, o compartilhamento, e os alertas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resumo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure o seu serviço &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mydlink.com/entrance&#34; title=&#34;Serviço MyDlink&#34;&gt;MyDlink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apresente sua câmera ao Sensr.net&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apresente o Sensr.net à sua câmera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detalhes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passo 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Para configurar a câmera, utilize o CD e as instruções disponibilizados em conjunto com a câmera. Tudo o que você precisa de fazer é conectar a câmera ao seu roteador e correr o software do CD. Você vai acabar por criar uma conta no site do MyDlink que vai dar acesso à sua câmera a partir do site ou dos aplicativos MyDlink. Após este passo, você conseguirá acessar sua câmera e alterar suas configurações. A página de configuração de sua câmera vai ter mais ou menos esse aspeto:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3077&#34; style=&#34;width: 410px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-5010L-Admin-br.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3077&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-5010L-Admin-br.png&#34; alt=&#34;Página Admin DCS-5010L&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;289&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-5010L-Admin-br.png 400w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-5010L-Admin-br-300x216.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Página Admin DCS-5010L
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agora você já consegue fazer alterações às configurações da câmera através do seu navegador. Se o que você pretende é assistir às filmagens em tempo real a partir de sua casa ou através do site MyDlink, então não será necessário fazer mais nada. (Existem outras configurações, como conexão sem fios e tamanho da imagem, que você pode alterar diretamente na interface, mas que eu não vou abordar nesse artigo.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adicione uma nova câmera à sua conta Sensr.net&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passo 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Faça o login no Sensr.net, utilizando o seu email e a sua senha. Se ainda não possui uma conta, você pode &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34; title=&#34;Cadastro gratuito no Sensr.net&#34;&gt;criar uma gratuitamente na página de inscrição&lt;/a&gt;. Depois de fazer login, clique no botão verde &lt;strong&gt;Add Camera&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3061&#34; style=&#34;width: 1013px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camerabr.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3061&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camerabr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Clique no botão verde&#34; width=&#34;1003&#34; height=&#34;339&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camerabr.png 1003w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camerabr-300x101.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1003px) 100vw, 1003px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Clique no botão verde
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Na página seguinte, você vai poder escolher o título (ou nome) da câmera, o fuso horário, a privacidade e o modelo. O título deve descrever o que a câmera está filmando. O título mais popular no Sensr.net é &lt;strong&gt;Porta da Frente&lt;/strong&gt;, que nos dá uma ideia de como os usuários utilizam o nosso site. Apesar de nós gerarmos um nome genérico para sua câmera baseado no login, você pode dar qualquer nome à sua câmera. O fuso horário é muito importante. Ele é utilizado para determinar a vista diária dos arquivos. Por padrão, as câmeras são privadas, o que significa que apenas você tem acesso a elas. Se quiser que sua câmera seja pública, você pode alterar essa configuração aqui. O modelo da câmera apenas indica qual o modelo que está sendo configurado. Nesse caso, o modelo é DCS-5010L.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3062&#34; style=&#34;width: 1009px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/add-camera-detailsbr.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3062&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/add-camera-detailsbr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dê um nome à sua câmera e partilhe alguns detalhes&#34; width=&#34;999&#34; height=&#34;491&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/add-camera-detailsbr.png 999w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/add-camera-detailsbr-300x147.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 999px) 100vw, 999px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Dê um nome à sua câmera e compartilhe alguns detalhes
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depois de preencher todos os detalhes e clicar no link &lt;strong&gt;Next Step&lt;/strong&gt;, nós vamos criar algumas credenciais FTP para você. Será necessário introduzir esses dados na sua câmera no próximo passo. Os dados com mais importância são:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Servidor FTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nome de usuário&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Senha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mantenha essa janela aberta ou copie os dados, uma vez que você vai precisar deles em breve. Você pode recuperar esses dados, a qualquer momento, na página de detalhes da câmera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3046&#34; style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3046&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708.png&#34; alt=&#34;Credenciais FTP&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;708&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708.png 1024w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708-300x207.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Credenciais FTP
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apresente sua câmera ao Sensr.net&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passo 3:&lt;/strong&gt; Agora é necessário configurar sua câmera para enviar imagens para o Sensr.net. Volte à página da DCS-5010L, fazendo o login no site MyDlink e clicando no link de configuração. Clique em “SETUP” no menu superior e, depois, em “FTP”, na lateral. Você vai ser encaminhado para essa página:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3078&#34; style=&#34;width: 330px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/FTP-DCS-5010L-BR.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3078&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/FTP-DCS-5010L-BR.png&#34; alt=&#34;Página Configuração FTP DCS-5010L&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;298&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/FTP-DCS-5010L-BR.png 320w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/FTP-DCS-5010L-BR-300x279.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 320px) 100vw, 320px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Página Configuração FTP DCS-5010L
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As setas vermelhas mostram os parâmetros que devem ser configurados. No campo Host Name, introduza o servidor FTP que fornecemos na página “Add Camera” no Sensr.net. Copie também o usuário e a senha. Escolha “Passive Mode”, uma vez que o Sensr.net suporta apenas o modo FTP passivo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;É também necessário configurar sua câmera para enviar imagens para o Sensr.net periodicamente. Para isso, selecione “Enable uploading to the FTP server” e confirme que “Always” e “1 Frames/Second” estão também selecionados. Estas são as configurações padrão e funcionam bem com o Sensr.net. As configurações padrão para o nome do ficheiro também são bem suportadas pelo serviço, por isso não existe necessidade de alterar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Não se esqueça de clicar no botão “Save Settings” localizado no topo da página. Após realizar este passo, a sua câmera DCS-5010L já estará enviando imagens para o Sensr.net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agora a configuração está terminada. Pode fechar a janela do navegador que mostra as configurações de sua câmera e voltar para o Sensr.net. Clique no botão &lt;strong&gt;Next Step&lt;/strong&gt; para ver as imagens enviadas pela sua câmera. Você verá uma página assim:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3050&#34; style=&#34;width: 997px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3050&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sucesso!&#34; width=&#34;987&#34; height=&#34;793&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo.png 987w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo-300x241.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 987px) 100vw, 987px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Sucesso!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agora que a sua câmera já está configurada, existem outras coisas que você pode fazer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adicionar alertas de movimento por SMS ou email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2012/04/11/guest-access-for-sensr-net-cameras/&#34; title=&#34;Acesso de outros usuários a uma câmera privada&#34;&gt;Convidar outros usuários para ver a sua câmera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2011/02/27/embed-your-sensr-net-cameras-live-view/&#34; title=&#34;Incorporar o streaming de vídeo em tempo real&#34;&gt;Incorporar o streaming de vídeo em tempo real no seu blog ou outro site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Criar um clipe de vídeo e compartilhar no Facebook, Twitter ou YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Se tiver alguma dificuldade ou pergunta, clique no botão de Feedback no lado direito de qualquer uma das páginas do Sensr.net e coloque a sua questão. Geralmente, nós nos esforçamos por responder no prazo máximo de 24h horas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensr.net Patched Against Shellshock Bug</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/09/26/sensr-net-patched-against-shellshock-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 20:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/09/26/sensr-net-patched-against-shellshock-bug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick note to let you know that Sensr.net has been patched against the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engadget.com/2014/09/25/what-is-the-shellshock/&#34; title=&#34;Shellshock Bash Bug&#34;&gt;shellshock bug&lt;/a&gt;.  We run mostly CentOS servers which were vulnerable to the bug.  Our crack devops team patched all these servers on September 24, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drop us an email if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Como Configurar a Gravação da D-Link DCS-5020L com Uploads FTP</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/09/26/como-configurar-a-gravacao-da-d-link-dcs-5020l-com-uploads-ftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 19:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/09/26/como-configurar-a-gravacao-da-d-link-dcs-5020l-com-uploads-ftp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3058&#34; style=&#34;width: 385px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-5020L-Dlink.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-3058 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-5020L-Dlink.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DCS-5020L da D-Link&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-5020L-Dlink.jpg 375w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-5020L-Dlink-250x300.jpg 250w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 375px) 100vw, 375px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    DCS-5020L da D-Link
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A câmera &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.dlink.com/products/connected-home/pan-tilt-daynight-network-camera/&#34; title=&#34;DCS 5020L&#34;&gt;D-Link DCS 5020L&lt;/a&gt; é um dos modelos mais populares da D-Link. Ela dispõe de visão noturna, rotação horizontal e vertical, WiFi e funciona com o serviço MyDlink. O valor da DCS 5020L é também muito acessível: atualmente &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/D-Link-Wireless-Surveillance-mydlink-Enabled-DCS-5020L/dp/B00CL8F98W/sensr-20&#34; title=&#34;DCS 5020L na Amazon&#34;&gt;ela custa $135 na Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Necessidade de Gravação&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apesar do serviço MyDlink permitir que você assista às filmagens da câmera remotamente, ele não suporta nenhum tipo de gravação ou armazenamento de imagens. É aqui que o Sensr.net entra. Nosso serviço permite armazenar automaticamente as imagens captadas no último mês. Este artigo vai ajudar você a configurar sua câmera DCS-5020L para que você veja tudo o que se passa com as suas coisas enquanto você não está olhando!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Também vou mostrar como configurar a câmera para enviar imagens para o site do&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;, para que você tire partido de todas as funcionalidades do nosso serviço, como o armazenamento, o compartilhamento, e os alertas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resumo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure o seu serviço &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mydlink.com/entrance&#34; title=&#34;Serviço MyDlink&#34;&gt;MyDlink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apresente sua câmera ao Sensr.net&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apresente o Sensr.net à sua câmera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detalhes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passo 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Para configurar a câmera, utilize o CD e as instruções disponibilizados em conjunto com o aparelho. Tudo o que você precisa de fazer é conectar a câmera ao seu roteador e correr o software do CD. Você vai acabar por criar uma conta no site do MyDlink que vai dar acesso à sua câmera a partir do site ou dos aplicativos MyDlink. Após este passo, você conseguirá acessar sua câmera e alterar suas configurações. A página de configuração de sua câmera vai ter mais ou menos esse aspeto:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3060&#34; style=&#34;width: 410px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-930L-AdminPage.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-3060 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-930L-AdminPage.png&#34; alt=&#34;Página de Admin da DCS-930L &#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;289&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-930L-AdminPage.png 400w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/DCS-930L-AdminPage-300x216.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Página de Admin da DCS-930L
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agora você já consegue fazer alterações às configurações da câmera através do seu navegador. Se o que você pretende é assistir às filmagens em tempo real a partir de sua casa ou através do site MyDlink, então não será necessário fazer mais nada. (Existem outras configurações, como conexão sem fios e tamanho da imagem, que você pode alterar diretamente na interface, mas que eu não vou abordar nesse artigo.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adicione uma nova câmera à sua conta Sensr.net&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passo 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Faça o login no Sensr.net, utilizando o seu email e a sua senha. Se ainda não possui uma conta, você pode &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34; title=&#34;Cadastro gratuito no Sensr.net  &#34;&gt;criar uma gratuitamente na página de inscrição&lt;/a&gt;. Depois de fazer login, clique no botão verde &lt;strong&gt;Add Camera&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3061&#34; style=&#34;width: 1013px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camerabr.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3061&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camerabr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Clique no botão verde&#34; width=&#34;1003&#34; height=&#34;339&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camerabr.png 1003w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camerabr-300x101.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1003px) 100vw, 1003px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Clique no botão verde
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Na página seguinte, você vai poder escolher o título (ou nome) da câmera, o fuso horário, a privacidade e o modelo. O título deve descrever o que a câmera está filmando. O título mais popular no Sensr.net é &lt;strong&gt;Porta da Frente&lt;/strong&gt;, que nos dá uma ideia de como os usuários utilizam o nosso site. Apesar de nós gerarmos um nome genérico para sua câmera baseado no login, você pode dar qualquer nome à sua câmera. O fuso horário é muito importante. Ele é utilizado para determinar a vista diária dos arquivos. Por padrão, as câmeras são privadas, o que significa que apenas você tem acesso a elas. Se quiser que sua câmera seja pública, você pode alterar essa configuração aqui. O modelo da câmera apenas indica qual o modelo que está sendo configurado. Nesse caso, o modelo é DCS-5020L.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3062&#34; style=&#34;width: 1009px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/add-camera-detailsbr.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3062&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/add-camera-detailsbr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dê um nome à sua câmera e partilhe alguns detalhes&#34; width=&#34;999&#34; height=&#34;491&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/add-camera-detailsbr.png 999w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/add-camera-detailsbr-300x147.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 999px) 100vw, 999px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Dê um nome à sua câmera e compartilhe alguns detalhes
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depois de preencher todos os detalhes e clicar no link &lt;strong&gt;Next Step&lt;/strong&gt;, nós vamos criar algumas credenciais FTP para você. Será necessário introduzir esses dados na sua câmera no próximo passo. Os dados com mais importância são:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Servidor FTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nome de usuário&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Senha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mantenha essa janela aberta ou copie os dados, uma vez que você vai precisar deles em breve. Você pode recuperar esses dados, a qualquer momento, na página de detalhes da câmera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3046&#34; style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3046&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708.png&#34; alt=&#34;Credenciais FTP&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;708&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708.png 1024w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708-300x207.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Credenciais FTP
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apresente sua câmera ao Sensr.net&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passo 3:&lt;/strong&gt; Agora é necessário configurar sua câmera para enviar imagens para o Sensr.net. Volte à página da DCS-5020L, fazendo o login no site MyDlink e clicando no link de configuração. Clique em “SETUP” no menu superior e, depois, em “FTP”, na lateral. Você vai ser encaminhado para essa página:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3064&#34; style=&#34;width: 330px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/dcs930ftpbr.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3064&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/dcs930ftpbr.png&#34; alt=&#34;DCS-5020L Página de configuração FTP &#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;298&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/dcs930ftpbr.png 320w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/dcs930ftpbr-300x279.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 320px) 100vw, 320px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    DCS-5020L Página de configuração FTP
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As setas vermelhas mostram os parâmetros que devem ser configurados. No campo Host Name, introduza o servidor FTP que fornecemos na página “Add Camera” no Sensr.net. Copie também o usuário e a senha. Escolha “Passive Mode”, uma vez que o Sensr.net suporta apenas o modo FTP passivo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;É também necessário configurar sua câmera para enviar imagens para o Sensr.net periodicamente. Para isso, selecione “Enable uploading to the FTP server” e confirme que “Always” e “1 Frames/Second” estão também selecionados. Estas são as configurações padrão e funcionam bem com o Sensr.net. As configurações padrão para o nome do ficheiro também são bem suportadas pelo serviço, por isso não existe necessidade de alterar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Não se esqueça de clicar no botão “Save Settings” localizado no topo da página. Após realizar este passo, a sua câmera DCS-5020L já estará enviando imagens para o Sensr.net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agora a configuração está terminada. Pode fechar a janela do navegador que mostra as configurações de sua câmera e voltar para o Sensr.net. Clique no botão &lt;strong&gt;Next Step&lt;/strong&gt; para ver as imagens enviadas pela sua câmera. Você verá uma página assim:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3050&#34; style=&#34;width: 997px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3050&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sucesso!&#34; width=&#34;987&#34; height=&#34;793&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo.png 987w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo-300x241.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 987px) 100vw, 987px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Sucesso!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agora que a sua câmera já está configurada, existem outras coisas que você pode fazer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adicionar alertas de movimento por SMS ou email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2012/04/11/guest-access-for-sensr-net-cameras/&#34; title=&#34;Acesso de outros usuários a uma câmera privada&#34;&gt;Convidar outros usuários para ver a sua câmera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2011/02/27/embed-your-sensr-net-cameras-live-view/&#34; title=&#34;Incorporar o streaming de vídeo em tempo real&#34;&gt;Incorporar o streaming de vídeo em tempo real no seu blog ou outro site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Criar um clipe de vídeo e compartilhar no Facebook, Twitter ou YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Se tiver alguma dificuldade ou pergunta, clique no botão de Feedback no lado direito de qualquer uma das páginas do Sensr.net e coloque a sua questão. Nós tentaremos responder no prazo máximo de 24h horas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Divirta-se!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Como configurar uma Foscam FI9821W V2 do Mac ou Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/09/25/como-configurar-uma-foscam-fi9821w-v2-do-mac-ou-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 07:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/09/25/como-configurar-uma-foscam-fi9821w-v2-do-mac-ou-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/11/foscamfi9821wv2black.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft wp-image-2577 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/11/foscamfi9821wv2black.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam FI9821W V2&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/11/foscamfi9821wv2black.jpg 160w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/11/foscamfi9821wv2black-150x150.jpg 150w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 160px) 100vw, 160px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Foscam-FI9821W-Megapixel-Wireless-Camera/dp/B00F3KWZW8/sensr-20&#34; title=&#34;Foscam FI9821W V2&#34;&gt;Foscam FI9821W V2&lt;/a&gt; é uma das câmeras IP mais populares atualmente. O seu valor ronda os $150 na &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Foscam-FI9821W-Megapixel-Wireless-Camera/dp/B00F3KWZW8/sensr-20&#34; title=&#34;Compre Foscam FI9821W V2 na Amazon&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. As instruções incluem um software de configuração da câmera para Windows e Mac, mas ele não é realmente necessário. Nesse artigo, vou mostrar como configurar a câmera sem o software. &lt;strong&gt;Tenha em atenção que a porta padrão dessa câmera é a 88&lt;/strong&gt;. Perdi 30 minutos para o perceber, e ainda mais tempo para entender o que isso significa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Também vou mostrar como enviar imagens para o&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;, para que você possa tirar partido de todas as nossas funcionalidades, como 30 dias de armanezamento, &lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2013/10/24/ip-camera-no-firewall-config/&#34; title=&#34;View IP Camera Remotely, No Firewall Config&#34;&gt;sem configuração do firewall&lt;/a&gt;, compartilhamento de vídeos, &lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2011/02/27/embed-your-sensr-net-cameras-live-view/&#34; title=&#34;Embed your Sensr.net camera’s live view&#34;&gt;streaming incorporável em tempo real&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2012/04/11/guest-access-for-sensr-net-cameras/&#34; title=&#34;Guest Access for Sensr.net Cameras&#34;&gt;acesso compartilhado com lista de usuários convidados&lt;/a&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resumo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conecte a câmera ao seu roteador e ligue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No seu roteador, veja qual o endereço IP da câmera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coloque o endereço IP da câmera no seu navegador e faça a sua configuração.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apresente a sua câmera ao Sensr.net.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apresente Sensr.net à sua câmera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detalhes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estou assumindo que você conseguiu executar sem problemas o Passo 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passo 2: Encontre o endereço de IP de seu roteador&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para executar o Passo 2, você necessita de fazer login no seu roteador. Você pode encontrar o endereço IP de seu roteador, consultando as configurações de seu computador. Num Mac você deve aceder a &lt;strong&gt;Network Settings &amp;gt; Advanced &amp;gt; TCP/IP&lt;/strong&gt;. No meu MacBook Pro, com sistema operativo Lion, eu vejo isso:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/Screen-Shot1-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-3037 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/Screen-Shot1-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen-Shot1-PM&#34; width=&#34;782&#34; height=&#34;694&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/Screen-Shot1-PM.png 782w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/Screen-Shot1-PM-300x266.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 782px) 100vw, 782px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;No Linux, você pode correr o comando &lt;strong&gt;ifconfig&lt;/strong&gt; para obter essa informação. No meu caso, esse comando indica que o meu roteador é 10.1.1.1. Uma configuração mais comum é 192.168.1.1, mas pode ser qualquer outra. Assim que você encontrar essa informação, aceda ao seu roteador inserindo &lt;a href=&#34;http://10.1.1.1&#34;&gt;http://10.1.1.1&lt;/a&gt; na barra de endereços de seu navegador (ou o endereço que você encontrou na sua rede). O mais provável é que você tenha de se conectar ao seu roteador. Os roteadores são muito diferentes entre si, vou mostrar as páginas do meu Netgear WPN824.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Após efetuar o login no seu roteador, encontre a página que mostra todos os dispositivos conectados. Em baixo mostro a página de meu roteador, selecionei &lt;strong&gt;Attached Devices&lt;/strong&gt;, à esquerda, e obtive essa lista.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3039&#34; style=&#34;width: 942px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/netgear-dispositivos-conectados.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-3039 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/netgear-dispositivos-conectados.png&#34; alt=&#34;Lista de dispositivos conectados&#34; width=&#34;932&#34; height=&#34;780&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/netgear-dispositivos-conectados.png 932w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/netgear-dispositivos-conectados-300x251.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 932px) 100vw, 932px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Lista de dispositivos conectados
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para encontrar a sua câmera IP, você precisa de procurar o endereço MAC de sua câmera. (O endereço MAC está num adesivo na base da câmera). Como o endereço MAC de minha câmera acaba em 97, utilizei a pesquisa Chrome (CMD-F) e busquei por :97. O endereço IP nesse caso foi 10.1.1.26.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passo 3: Direcione seu navegador para o endereço de IP da câmera e faça sua configuração&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para chegar à sua câmera, direcione seu navegador para o endereço IP que você encontrou. Nesse caso, &lt;a href=&#34;http://10.1.1.26:88&#34;&gt;http://10.1.1.26:88&lt;/a&gt;. Não se esqueça de incluir a porta :88, como indiquei no início do artigo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Descobri que o Chrome, no Mac, não apresenta a página corretamente, mas o Safari consegue fazer um bom trabalho. Existem alguns plugins que você pode utilizar com o Chrome, mas é muito mais fácil usar o Safari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quando você acessa à página de sua câmera, ela terá esse aspeto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3040&#34; style=&#34;width: 650px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-pagina-configuracao.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-3040 size-large&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-pagina-configuracao-1024x708.png&#34; alt=&#34;Página de Configuração da FI9821W V2&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;442&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-pagina-configuracao-1024x708.png 1024w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-pagina-configuracao-300x207.png 300w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-pagina-configuracao.png 1141w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Página de Configuração da FI9821W V2
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No Safari, você pode clicar no separador de Live Video e ver a sua câmera. A partir dessa página você pode rodar a sua câmera horizontal e verticalmente e assistir ao vídeo por streaming em tempo real a partir de sua rede doméstica. Hoje, algumas árvores estão sendo cortadas lá fora, por isso decidi instalar a câmera para observar o processo. É assim que você vai ver o vídeo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3042&#34; style=&#34;width: 650px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-live-video-pagina.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-large wp-image-3042&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-live-video-pagina-1024x708.png&#34; alt=&#34;Vídeo em tempo real no Safari&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;442&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-live-video-pagina-1024x708.png 1024w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-live-video-pagina-300x207.png 300w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-live-video-pagina.png 1141w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Vídeo em tempo real no Safari
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Você pode ver na tela anterior que estou correndo a última versão de firmware, 10.11.1.18.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atualize o Firmware para a versão 1.11.1.18 ou superior&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A última versão de firmware é a ideal para que sua câmera trabalhe na perfeição com o &lt;a href=&#34;http://Sensr.net&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;. (Siga as instruções cuidadosamente. Se ainda não está correndo a versão 1.11.1.16, você precisa de fazer uma atualização para essa versão e só depois atualizar para a última versão 1.11.1.18. A minha câmera tinha a versão 1.11.1.15, por isso tive de fazer uma dupla atualização. A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foscam.com/down3.aspx&#34;&gt;última versão de firmware pode ser encontrada aqui&lt;/a&gt; e o &lt;a href=&#34;http://foscam.us/forum/new-firmware-for-fi9821w-v2-released-t7237.html&#34; title=&#34;Comunicado versão 1.11.1.18 &#34;&gt;comunicado pode ser visto aqui&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passo 4: Apresente a sua câmera ao Sensr.net&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adicione uma Câmera Nova à sua conta&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faça o login em sua conta Sensr.net e selecione &lt;strong&gt;Add Camera&lt;/strong&gt;. Sensr.net tem um período de teste gratuito, por isso experimente e veja se é aquilo de que estava à procura. (Criar uma conta no Sensr.net. é gratuito. Após terminar o seu período de teste gratuito, o controlo da câmera custa desde $9.95/mês). Assim que você fizer o login, você vai ver uma página como essa:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3044&#34; style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-novo-usuario-1024x708.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3044&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-novo-usuario-1024x708.png&#34; alt=&#34;Página para adicionar uma nova câmera&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;708&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-novo-usuario-1024x708.png 1024w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-novo-usuario-1024x708-300x207.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Página para adicionar uma nova câmera
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A seguir, você vai ver essa página, onde você pode definir o fuso horário para a sua câmera, atribuir um nome, e indicar-nos o modelo. Todas as câmeras ficam predefinidas como privadas, mas você pode alterar sua privacidade para pública se você quiser compartilhar as filmagens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3045&#34; style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera2-1024x708.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3045&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera2-1024x708.png&#34; alt=&#34;Passo 1&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;708&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera2-1024x708.png 1024w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera2-1024x708-300x207.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Passo 1
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Após você realizar esses passos, nós vamos gerar credenciais FTP para a sua câmera. Isso vai gerar um login para a sua FI9821W V2 para onde pode ser feito o upload de imagens por FTP. Esse dado diz à sua câmera para onde deve ser feito o upload. Os dados com mais importância são:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Servidor FTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nome de usuário FTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Senha FTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guarde esses dados para que possamos incluí-los mais tarde.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3046&#34; style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3046&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708.png&#34; alt=&#34;Credenciais FTP&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;708&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708.png 1024w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-ftp-1024x708-300x207.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Credenciais FTP
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passo 5: Apresente Sensr.net à sua câmera&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agora é necessário configurar a sua câmera para enviar imagens ao Sensr.net. Volte à página de configuração da câmera usando o endereço de IP que descobrimos anteriormente. Selecione Network e, depois, FTP Settings. A página apresentada será:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3047&#34; style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-ftp-pagina-1024x708.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3047&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-ftp-pagina-1024x708.png&#34; alt=&#34;Configurar FTP&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;708&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-ftp-pagina-1024x708.png 1024w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-ftp-pagina-1024x708-300x207.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Configurar FTP
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduza no primeiro campo o Servidor FTP da página de configuração do Sensr.net. Vai aparecer dessa forma &lt;a href=&#34;ftp://f9.sensr.net/&#34;&gt;ftp://f9.sensr.net/&lt;/a&gt; ou qualquer outro servidor que o Sensr.net atribuiu à sua câmera. Atualmente os nossos servidores têm designação de f0.sensr.net a f9.sensr.net. Mantenha a porta 21 e o FTP mode como PASV. O nome de usuário é único para a sua câmera, por isso utilize o que foi atribuído pelo Sensr.net. O mesmo se aplica para a senha. O melhor é copiar e colar, para evitar erros no processo. Clique no botão de teste e a FI9821W vai verificar os dados de login. Se aparecer uma mensagem de &lt;strong&gt;Sucesso&lt;/strong&gt;, o processo foi concluído. Caso contrário, verifique se os dados do servidor, nome de usuário e senha estão corretos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sugerimos que configure a câmera para enviar uma imagem por segundo. Assim, você vai conseguir ver a gravação em tempo real a partir do Sensr.net. Para isso, acesse a página Video/Snapshot Settings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3048&#34; style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-snapshot-pagina-1024x708.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3048&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-snapshot-pagina-1024x708.png&#34; alt=&#34;Configuração Vídeo &gt; Snapshots&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;708&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-snapshot-pagina-1024x708.png 1024w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/fi9821wv2-snapshot-pagina-1024x708-300x207.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Configuração Vídeo &gt; Snapshots
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aqui você pode adicionar 1 como intervalo para que a câmera faça o upload contínuo de um frame por segundo. Selecione também todos os intervalos de tempo para que a câmera faça o upload 24h por dia, 7 dias por semana. Para salvar as configurações, não se esqueça de clicar no botão Save, no topo. Assim que terminar esses passos, a sua câmera FI9821WV2 começará a fazer o upload para o Sensr.net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No Sensr.net a página deve passar desse aspeto:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3049&#34; style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera3-1024x708.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3049&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera3-1024x708.png&#34; alt=&#34;A aguardar o upload&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;708&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera3-1024x708.png 1024w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera3-1024x708-300x207.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    A aguardar o upload
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para uma página que mostra a imagem que sua câmera enviou. Algo como:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3050&#34; style=&#34;width: 997px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3050&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sucesso!&#34; width=&#34;987&#34; height=&#34;793&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo.png 987w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/09/sensr-add-camera-successo-300x241.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 987px) 100vw, 987px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Sucesso!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muitos parabéns, acabou a configuração de sua câmera. A sua câmera está agora ligada ao Sensr.net. Vamos arquivar todos os movimentos, disponibilizando 30 dias de arquivos, SMS e alertas de email, acesso livre à sua lista de convidados e muito mais. Você pode assistir em tempo real ao streaming de vídeo a partir de nosso site ou dos nossos aplicativos. Não é necessário configurar um firewall, nem ter um PC na cave para observar as imagens de sua câmera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Se surgir alguma dificuldade, envie um email para info @ sensr.net e nós vamos tentar ajudar você!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup the Panasonic BL-C30A Network Cam with Cloud Recording</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/08/13/how-to-setup-the-panasonic-bl-c30a-network-cam-with-cloud-recording/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 16:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2014/08/13/how-to-setup-the-panasonic-bl-c30a-network-cam-with-cloud-recording/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft wp-image-3022&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/08/41BE0QTS8KL1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;41BE0QTS8KL&#34; width=&#34;345&#34; height=&#34;345&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/08/41BE0QTS8KL1.jpg 500w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/08/41BE0QTS8KL1-150x150.jpg 150w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/08/41BE0QTS8KL1-300x300.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 345px) 100vw, 345px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  Despite looking like it belongs in the 90s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Panasonic-Wireless-802-11-Network-BL-C30A/dp/B0002GS4ZA/ref=sr_1_12?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1407868581&amp;sr=8-12&amp;keywords=Network+cameras/sensr-20&#34;&gt;Panasonic BL-C30A&lt;/a&gt; actually boasts some great reviews. It is easy to setup and provides a pretty high quality video. It might not be the most sleek or attractive camera on the market but it will get the job done and its built by a very large and reputable company which is a plus for a lot of people. In this tutorial I will show you how to get this bad boy setup and streaming to the cloud with Sensr.net so you can watch your stuff from anywhere at anytime.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  I&amp;#8217;ve broken this tutorial up into steps to make it easier to follow:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup your hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find your camera&amp;#8217;s IP address and go to the network access page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Sensr.net and get FTP credentials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell your camera about your new FTP credentials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to skip around if you are confident you can accomplish some setups without reading the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step one: Setup your hardware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know if this part even counts as a tutorial because my instructions are pretty simple: set your hardware. Seriously just plug that camera in. Plug it into your router and a wall outlet and you are done. Boom. That was fast. If you want your camera to connect using wireless just hold off on that for now and we can fix it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step two: Find your camera&amp;#8217;s IP address and go to the network access page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always I suggest doing this by going through your router.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will show you how to do this on a mac (because I am writing from a mac) but it is also very easy to do from a PC (the PC process is outlined in &lt;a style=&#34;color: #888888;&#34; href=&#34;http://blogs.computerworld.com/network-security/22777/find-ip-address-your-home-router&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;). On my mac it is under system preferences&amp;gt;Network&amp;gt;Advanced…&amp;gt;TCP/IP. The page looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;color: #888888;&#34; href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/Screen-Shot-2013-12-09-at-6.02.37-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2597&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/Screen-Shot-2013-12-09-at-6.02.37-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Router IP address shown on second line&#34; width=&#34;782&#34; height=&#34;694&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/Screen-Shot-2013-12-09-at-6.02.37-PM.png 782w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/Screen-Shot-2013-12-09-at-6.02.37-PM-300x266.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 782px) 100vw, 782px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the IP address just enter it into your browser and it should bring you to a network access page. Everyone’s looks different depending on the make and model of their browser. Mine, for example, looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;color: #888888;&#34; href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/netgear-attached-devices.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2599&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/netgear-attached-devices.png&#34; alt=&#34;My router&#39;s Network Access portal&#34; width=&#34;932&#34; height=&#34;780&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/netgear-attached-devices.png 932w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/netgear-attached-devices-300x251.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 932px) 100vw, 932px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t sure which device is new you can always unplug your camera then plug it back in to see which one disappears and comes back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you&amp;#8217;ve got the camera&amp;#8217;s IP address just type it into your browser. There will be an authentication window with the username and password already. SAVE THOSE.  Now you should come to a page that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3024&#34; style=&#34;width: 441px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/08/Screen-Shot-2014-08-13-at-12.26.13-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3024&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/08/Screen-Shot-2014-08-13-at-12.26.13-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;First time on network access page&#34; width=&#34;431&#34; height=&#34;171&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/08/Screen-Shot-2014-08-13-at-12.26.13-PM.png 431w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/08/Screen-Shot-2014-08-13-at-12.26.13-PM-300x119.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 431px) 100vw, 431px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    First time on network access page
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have to install a plug-in. Go ahead and do that and now you will have full access to the camera. Explore this page when you have time to find out what your camera can really do. For now it is onto step three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step three: Go to Sensr.net and get FTP credentials.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you are ready to setup stuff from the Sensr.net side of things. We will store all your recorded data in the cloud so you can access it from any device, anywhere. We have a number of different plans but the first week is always free so just set it up and give it a try. If you don’t like it you don’t need to continue to a payed plan. Log into your Sensr.net account click the &lt;strong&gt;Add Camera&lt;/strong&gt; button. Once you login you’ll see a page like this: &lt;a style=&#34;color: #888888;&#34; href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/02/sensr-add-camera.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2714&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/02/sensr-add-camera.png&#34; alt=&#34;Add new camera page&#34; width=&#34;1003&#34; height=&#34;339&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/02/sensr-add-camera.png 1003w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/02/sensr-add-camera-300x101.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1003px) 100vw, 1003px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Next you’ll see a page like this where you can set the timezone for your camera, give it a name, and tell us the model.  Cameras default to private but you can make them public if you want to share them with the world. &lt;a style=&#34;color: #888888;&#34; href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/02/add-camera-details.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2713&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/02/add-camera-details.png&#34; alt=&#34;Note this is for a different device&#34; width=&#34;999&#34; height=&#34;491&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/02/add-camera-details.png 999w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2014/02/add-camera-details-300x147.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 999px) 100vw, 999px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;After that, we’ll generate some FTP credentials for your server. This generates a login for your  Panasonic to where it can upload images via FTP. This tells your camera where to upload the images. The important information here is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FTP Server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FTP User name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FTP Password&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save these so we can add them to your camera later. &lt;a style=&#34;color: #888888;&#34; href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-s2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2607&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-s2.png&#34; alt=&#34;FTP credentials&#34; width=&#34;1141&#34; height=&#34;790&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-s2.png 1141w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-s2-300x207.png 300w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-s2-1024x708.png 1024w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1141px) 100vw, 1141px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the last step&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Step four: Tell your camera about your new FTP credentials.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Go back to the network access page. Click on the setup tab then go to Buffer/Transfer. Click No and check enable Buffer/Transfer then choose timer for the trigger. Click next the choose always on the schedule page. Set the image resolution and quality as high as you like and choose one image per second on the next page. Choose FTP then Copy and Paste the credentials you got earlier. Make sure the port is set to 21 and the mode is set to passive. Hit save and you are done.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Go back to the Sensr.net tab and it should look like this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_2618&#34; style=&#34;width: 997px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-success.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2618&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-success.png&#34; alt=&#34;Success!&#34; width=&#34;987&#34; height=&#34;793&#34; srcset=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-success.png 987w, http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-success-300x241.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 987px) 100vw, 987px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Success!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, now you’re done with the camera config. You’re camera is now on Sensr.net. We’ll archive all the motion events, giving you 30 days of archives, SMS and email alerts, guest access, and a whole lot more.  You can view the live stream on our website or in our apps.  No firewall configuration is needed.  No PC in the basement required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any problems, send email to info @ sensr.net and we’ll try to help you out!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>