<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sensr.net Blog | Watch your Stuff!</title>
    <link>http://blog.sensr.net/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sensr.net Blog | Watch your Stuff!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 09:00:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.sensr.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>An Alternative to Nest Cam</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/05/an-alternative-to-nest-cam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 09:00:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/05/an-alternative-to-nest-cam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/nest-cam.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Nest Cam Indoor HD Camera&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;No doubt about it, Nest Cam is easy to setup and use.  But there are a number of drawbacks to using Nest Cam
that might entice you to try an alternative like &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;.  Here are some reasons that you
might want to try an alternative to Nest Cam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t use your own camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t mix and match camera models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The service is expensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No APIs for accessing your footage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Locked in to one vendor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited video clips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in using Sensr.net as an alternative to using Nest Cam, give us a try.  We have a
free trial of course.  Any you can use almost any camera with our service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s go into the details of why you might want an alternative to Nest Cam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;flexible-camera-choice&#34;&gt;Flexible camera choice&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time with Nest Cam you had only one choice, an indoor camera. Now Nest Cam comes in two flavors, indoor
and outdoor. But what if you don&amp;rsquo;t like these solutions? Besides being expensive, the form factor just might not fit
your needs. What if you want a dome camera? Or a camera that you can pan, tilt, and zoom? PTZ (pan, tilt, zoom)
cameras are very common but Nest doesn&amp;rsquo;t have one. What if you want a telephoto lens or a spy camera? Sorry, but
with Nest Cam you&amp;rsquo;re out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get HD security cameras on Amazon for under $40. Nest Cam starts at $199. If you&amp;rsquo;re technically savvy and
don&amp;rsquo;t mind doing a little work in setting up the camera, you can use a service like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; for your Cloud DVR with your $40 camera and save a lot of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Sensr.net you can even use cameras from different manufacturers.  You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be stuck to one brand.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/SensrNestCompare.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;With Sensr.net you can use almost any camera!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;limited-video-clips&#34;&gt;Limited Video Clips&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Nest Cam you&amp;rsquo;re limited to 3 hours of clips. On Sensr.net we don&amp;rsquo;t limit the number of &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2014/04/29/making-clips-on-sensr-net/&#34;&gt;clips you
make&lt;/a&gt;. We store them on our servers as long as you have a valid account. We
also email you a link to download the clip every time you make one. You&amp;rsquo;ll have your own copy and can do anything
you want with it. Give it to the police, stick it in your Dropbox folder for future reference, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;flexible-and-programmatic-access&#34;&gt;Flexible and Programmatic access&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Sensr.net you can use &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/02/07/new-sensr-net-api-v3/&#34;&gt;our APIs&lt;/a&gt; to write code to access your camera data
that is stored in the cloud. Don&amp;rsquo;t like how we generate clips? Write your own code to do a better job. Sure, this is
not a feature that most users will want, but we think it&amp;rsquo;s kind of cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limited-storage&#34;&gt;Limited storage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nest Cam will give you 10 days of storage for $10. For the same price with Sensr.net you get a month of storage. We
also give you unlimited storage of favorites images and clips. Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/plans&#34;&gt;our pricing&lt;/a&gt; for
more details. We have annual plans that save you even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/SensrNestChart.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;With Sensr.net you can use almost any camera!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you like the idea of using a Cloud DVR for your security cameras, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to be locked in to one
camera brand, make sure you explore other alternatives and give Sensr.net a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Best Nest Cam Alternative Yet written by: Vation
The Best Nest Cam Alternative Yet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you tired of your nest cam? Are you exhausted from paying so much money only to have about 3 hours of clipping, does 10 days for 10 dollars seem a bit pricey to you? Well, we got you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At sensr, we seek to provide you with cloud dvr storage of your choice, for a price you won’t help but want to pay and guess what? It’s all up to your personal preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who Are We?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a wifi security camera and cloud dvr storage company that seek to provide security camera users with a cheaper and more interesting alternative to nest cam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why Us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side by side comparison:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nest cam Sensr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· One vendor As many as you prefer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Single camera Multiple cameras&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Expensive Affordable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Limited clip time Limitless clip time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Limited storage Limitless cloud dvr storage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full review:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your camera, your choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, most users who needed surveillance were stuck with the option of the camera provided by the company. This sometimes meant that they had to pay for expensive cameras which may not have provided them with the kind of clarity or footage quality they wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At sensr, we give our clients the flexibility of choosing the Ip camera they want. This is based on the fact that there are some amazing Ip cameras online that do not necessarily cost a fortune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our clients can also mix camera from different manufacturers however they please. We seek to ensure that the client’s happiness is what comes first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As many clips as you want, as long as you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the older providers limited the number of video clips to a maximum of 3hours, we allow you as our user to create as many clips as you want without the constraint of having to worry about what is important and what is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage, storage, storage!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world existing in cloud storage, we provide the best there is in cloud dvr. Our servers can hold as much data as you want them to at a price that is affordable. Check our pricing here (). These service is available to you as long as you have a valid email account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great news is that the longer the plan you choose, the greater the save.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access your clippings at the touch of a button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With nest came and the other alternatives, you only found as much of your clippings as they could provide. With sensr, however, all the data is available to you using our APIs. These allow you to code for access to our cloud storage. There is also the option of generating your own codes however way you please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affordable for all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a variety of plans available that are great for first time beginners, indoor and outdoor lighting and all scenarios which may not have been addressed with the older security cameras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free trials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great news is that we offer free trials to all who are interested. If you like what you see, and we are sure you will, you can sign up for your own account and regain the control of your Wi-Fi security cameras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrap up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At sensr, we seek to be the best nest cam alternative available that is both user friendly and flexible in the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try us today for free!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ouvis ZV1 Camera Not Ready for Prime Time</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/05/ouvis-zv1-camera-not-ready-for-prime-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 10:49:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/05/ouvis-zv1-camera-not-ready-for-prime-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/veezon-Wireless-Camera-Android-iPhone/dp/B00WZOF9LE/sensr-20&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/ouvis-zv1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Useless Ouvis ZV1&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Ouvis ZV1 camera is not ready for prime time. The only thing it&amp;rsquo;s good for is viewing the camera on your local
network. You can&amp;rsquo;t view it remotely (no P2P viewing) and the FTP uploads don&amp;rsquo;t work so you can&amp;rsquo;t use it with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing good about this camera is that it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy to setup. If you have the app, you can get the camera
going pretty easily. You do need to plug it into an ethernet jack on the same network as your phone&amp;rsquo;s wifi, but once
you do that, the Ouvis app can find the camera and configure it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;useless-ftp-config&#34;&gt;Useless FTP Config&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike other cameras like the Tenvis or the Foscam, there is no P2P functionality.  This means you can&amp;rsquo;t watch
the camera remotely unless you do some port forwarding magic.   Here at Sensr.net we don&amp;rsquo;t like to do port forwarding, we prefer to have our cameras push rather than have to &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/10/24/ip-camera-no-firewall-config/&#34;&gt;opening holes in a firewall.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the Ouvis ZV1 FTP doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.  You can configure it but you can&amp;rsquo;t test it or use it.  I have no idea what the FTP configuration does, maybe it sends the info back to China where they keep it for future use.  Who knows.  What they don&amp;rsquo;t do is allow you to upload images or videos to your own FTP server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:30%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/OuvisAddCamera.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Country selection Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;width:30%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/OuvisFTP.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Country selection Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;doesn-t-work-with-sensr-net&#34;&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with Sensr.net&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use Sensr.net you need to be able to FTP Jpeg images.  Thus the Ouvis is useless when it comes to using
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; or even viewing the camera remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;give-tenvis-a-try&#34;&gt;Give Tenvis a Try&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intead of the Ouvis I would recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2014/07/03/how-to-setup-the-tenvis-iprobot3-with-cloud-recording/&#34;&gt;trying the
Tenvis&lt;/a&gt;. The setup is easy, it supports P2P
viewing, and it works with &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Wifi hack: Connecting to old static IPs</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/04/google-wifi-hack-connecting-to-old-static-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 08:58:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/04/google-wifi-hack-connecting-to-old-static-ips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2017/04/google-wifi-hack-connecting-to-old-static-ips/&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/gwifi.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Google Wifi Router&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Are you setting up a new Wifi router and have a bunch of devices with static IPs? When converting to the Gogle Wifi
router, I discovered a cool hack to get to your devices with their old IP addresses even though the router is using
a new subnet or IP range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://madeby.google.com/wifi/&#34;&gt;Google Wifi&lt;/a&gt; is a cool way to blanket your home with wifi. Place multiple
nodes around your home and the create a mesh network among the nodes. Each node has multiple ethernet jacks. Only
the primary node needs to be plugged into your router. On the secondary nodes, the ethernet jacks allow you to
connect ethernet devices to the network directly. Essentially the nodes act as if they are wired. You can plug a
printer or camera or desktop computer into the nodes. One drawback to the Google Wifi is that you &lt;em&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; connect
them using a wired network. This is contrast to the competing &lt;a href=&#34;https://eero.com&#34;&gt;eero&lt;/a&gt; system which allows the nodes
to be connected via a wired network as well as using the mesh network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-those-static-ips&#34;&gt;What about those static IPs?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges to using the Google Wifi is you need to convert all of your devices to the new network. In my
case I was using the private subnet 10.1.1.x. If you&amp;rsquo;re using DCHP this isn&amp;rsquo;t a big deal, but in my case I had a
bunch of cameras with fixed IP addreses like 10.1.1.60 so I could connect to them directly and also setup port
forwarding for external access. My main reason for doing this was so I could easily connect to the cameras directly.
If you use DHCP, the IP addresses of the cameras will change over time and if you want to connect to them, you need
to &lt;em&gt;rediscover&lt;/em&gt; the camera&amp;rsquo;s IP address, which can be a pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, with the Google Wifi, finding the IP addresses of devices on the network is now very easy. The accompaning
Google Wifi app will let you see all the devices connected to your network. You can give them nicknames, and so you
can easily find the device when the IP address changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most devices the switchover is easy, once the Google Wifi is up with the same SSID and password as your old
network, the cameras will switch over. However, if a camera is setup using a fixed (static) IP address, you&amp;rsquo;re
stuck. You can do a factory reset on the camera and set it up on the new subnet, but you&amp;rsquo;ll have to change all the
settings again to get it back into the state it was in before. For instance if you use
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to reconfigure the FTP uploading, which is a hassle. You can connect to
the camera directly using ethernet and reset the IP address or change it to DHCP, but if the camera is already
using a static IP, I thought there would be no way to get to it with the new Google Wifi router, but I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a camera with a fixed IP but you&amp;rsquo;ve switched over to Google Wifi. Now you can&amp;rsquo;t get to the device
since it&amp;rsquo;s using a different IP range, say 10.1.1.x. There is a way to connect directly to the camera even if it&amp;rsquo;s
using a different IP range than what is being used on the wifi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-camera-is-the-router&#34;&gt;The camera is the router&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick that worked for me was to use the IP address of the camera as the router address for my laptop. In my
case I was able to connect to my camera over the Google WIFI network even though the old camera didn&amp;rsquo;t have an IP
address on the Google Wifi subnet. My old network had the router IP of 10.1.1.1 and my camera had the IP of
10.1.1.244. I could connect to 10.1.1.244 by setting the IP address of my laptop manually to 10.1.1.48 (48 is just
random here, anything but 244 would work I think) and then setting the router IP on my laptop to 10.1.1.244. Since
10.1.1.244 is the IP of the camera my laptop was sending packets to the camera directly. This seems like a neat
trick that could save you a lot of hassle. In my case, cameras were mounted up high and I would need to get out a
ladder to reach them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I connected to the IP camera on 10.1.1.244 I then changed it&amp;rsquo;s network settings to use dhcp and now I can
connect to it directly without having to mess with changing my IP.  Now everything is happy and running on the
new Google Wifi network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried this with other wifi routers, but I&amp;rsquo;m guessing it would work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;try-sensr-net-for-free&#34;&gt;Try Sensr.net for free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do have an IP camera and want to record it in the cloud, give
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; a try. We work with most off the shelf cameras. As long as your
camera can FTP JPEGs (and most can) then you can use our service.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to configure a Foscam FI9900P Outdoor Camera from Mac or Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/04/how-to-configure-a-foscam-fi9900p-outdoor-camera-from-mac-or-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 09:59:35 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/04/how-to-configure-a-foscam-fi9900p-outdoor-camera-from-mac-or-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2017/04/how-to-configure-a-foscam-fi9900p-outdoor-camera-from-mac-or-linux/&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FI9900P.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Foscam FI9900P Outdoor HD Camera&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Foscam-FI9900P-Outdoor-Wireless-Camera/dp/B011US2ADK/sensr-20&#34;&gt;Foscam FI9900P Outdoor HD Wireless Security Camera&lt;/a&gt;
is a recent compact outdoor model from Foscam.  It&amp;rsquo;s currently listing for around $125
on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest gripe with this camera is the mounting hardware.  The camera can
only be pointed forward and tilted up and down.  There is no left or right articulation.
In my case I was mounting the camera near the wall my garage.  I had to put a little shim
under one side of the mounting brack to get it to angle off to the side.  See the image
below for the final orientation.  If I had mounted it straight ahead, I would have
ended up with half the frame taken up by the left wall.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/fi9900p-garage.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/fi9900p-garage.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Had to angle camera manually to get a more centered image.  The image quality is quite good though.&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The camera works well with Sensr.net, so you can use our cloud DVR service with the Foscam.  We have a free trial, so sign up and follow the instructions below on how to get it working with Sensr.net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera is easy to setup using the Foscam app.  The setup for this camera is
pretty much the same as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/ftp-setup-on-the-foscam-wireless-security-camera-1920tvl/&#34;&gt;Foscam R2 aka 1920tvl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;interesting-features-in-the-foscam-app&#34;&gt;Interesting Features in the Foscam App&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/foscam/id924381688?mt=8&#34;&gt;Foscam app&lt;/a&gt; seems to work. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s filled with grammatical mistakes, but they will fix those over time.
It let&amp;rsquo;s you share the images on &lt;strong&gt;WeChat&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;WeChat Moments&lt;/strong&gt;, whatever that is. (Ok, it&amp;rsquo;s the Facebook &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wechat.com/en/&#34;&gt;Messenger of
China&lt;/a&gt;, but not really very important to the non-Chinese market.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:30%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamAmerica.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Country selection Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;width:30%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamWechat.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wechat Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;width:30%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamFirmware.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Firware upgrade Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a selection for United States but you can select &lt;em&gt;America&lt;/em&gt;, which is kind
of the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe the best new feature is that you can upgrade the firmware in the app! Excellent! Now when
there is a security issue in the firmware, the app will make it simple to perform the upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-s-missing&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s missing?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has a lot of controls but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the local IP address for the camera. If you&amp;rsquo;re
going to setup this camera for FTP you&amp;rsquo;ll need to find it&amp;rsquo;s IP address. Normally I would
recommend connecting to your router and looking for the device with a matching MAC address. This
will work if you&amp;rsquo;re using the wired connection. The MAC address is printed on the bottom of the
camera. However, the wireless MAC address is not. It would be nice if the app would tell you the
URL to connect to the web interface. If you&amp;rsquo;ve already put your amera on wifi, you can still
find it but you may have to try connecting to a bunch of different IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;port-88&#34;&gt;Port 88!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to connect to the camera, make sure to use port 88. For some reason the default
port for Foscam is 88. That means you&amp;rsquo;ll have to go to &lt;code&gt;http://IP:88/&lt;/code&gt; to get to the web
interface. For example, if your camera&amp;rsquo;s IP is &lt;code&gt;172.16.20.73&lt;/code&gt; you&amp;rsquo;ll need to go to
&lt;code&gt;http://172.16.20.73:88/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;safari-plugins&#34;&gt;Safari Plugins!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using a Mac, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install plugins. I really wish these camera manufacturers
would just use web standards instead of making us install software. I tried configuring the
camera without the plugins, but it really seems to enforce this. Maybe future versions of the
app will support FTP configuration so we can skip the browser all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;configure-the-ftp-server&#34;&gt;Configure the FTP Server&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Log on to your account at &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; and click the add camera button. This
will give you the three pieces of information you need to configure your camera: server,
username, and password. Our server names are &lt;code&gt;f0.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt; through &lt;code&gt;f9.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt;. The
usernames are &lt;code&gt;camNNN&lt;/code&gt; where &lt;code&gt;NNN&lt;/code&gt; is an integer. The password is generated randomly. Be careful
since in a password some characters can be confused. Zeros and Os looks alike. Ones and Ls also
look alike. It&amp;rsquo;s best to copy and paste the passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have these, you can then go to the FTP sever page on the camera, which looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamFTPSettings.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FTP server URL shows a dir at the end. On the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; side we just
ignore this. You can add it if you wish but it&amp;rsquo;s not needed. Your URL should start with FTP
though, like this: &lt;code&gt;ftp://fX.sensr.net/&lt;/code&gt;, where X is the server that
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; tells you to use for your camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;configure-snapshot-settings&#34;&gt;Configure Snapshot Settings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you&amp;rsquo;ll want to configure the snapshot settings, which tells the camera to upload JPEG
snapshots to &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;. We recommend you send an image per second to our
servers. (See &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/10/24/ip-camera-no-firewall-config/&#34;&gt;No Firewall Config&lt;/a&gt; for more details
on why we recommend this.) This way we can generate a live Motion JPEG stream (MJPEG) on the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; site. Make sure to select all in the upper left hand corner of
the schedule so the camera will always upload. If you don&amp;rsquo;t want us to process images on certain
days or certain hours, this is the place to configure that. Make sure to click the Save button
at the top. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve done this your Foscam should start uploading to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamSnapshotSettings.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; side the page should go from this:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-s3.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt; Waiting for upload&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To a page that shows the image your camera uploaded.  Something like this:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-success.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Success!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, now you&amp;rsquo;re done with the camera config. Your camera is now on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ll archive all the motion
events, giving you 30 days of archives, SMS and email alerts, guest access, and a whole lot more.  You can view the live stream on our website
or in our apps. No firewall configuration is needed. No PC in the basement required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any problems, send email to info @ sensr.net and we&amp;rsquo;ll try to help you out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;don-t-set-scheduled-recording&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Set Scheduled Recording&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be tempted to set the Scheduled Recording.  This is for MKV video files.  If you upload those to Sensr.net we&amp;rsquo;ll just remove
them, since we only support JPEG files right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/UnsetFoscamScheduledRecording.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;don-t-set-motion-detection-settings&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Set Motion Detection Settings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also don&amp;rsquo;t need the motion detection settings to work with Sensr.net.  We do the motion detection on the server side.
See our blog post &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2011/07/25/true-meaning-of-motion-detection-off/&#34;&gt;The True Meaning of Motion Detection Off&lt;/a&gt;
for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamMotionDetectionSettings.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with this camera. I didn&amp;rsquo;t put it outside but I think it would work
well outdoors if you can get it connected to power. There is another more expensive model, the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Foscam-FI9901EP-Weatherproof-Detection-One-Click/dp/B01LXWLK3N/
sensr-20&#34;&gt;FI9901EP&lt;/a&gt; which supports POE (power over ethernet) so you can run just a single wire to the
camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretty cheap at $125&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good image quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works well with &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difficult to aim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live view &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2017/02/foscam-offline-why-cant-i-view-my-camera-live/&#34;&gt;often fails&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missing IP address in app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more, check out this YouTube video that walks through the setup.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/WNTnvJkeRT0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do port forwarding with eero</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/04/how-to-do-port-forwarding-with-eero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 10:06:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/04/how-to-do-port-forwarding-with-eero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/eero-home.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;eero wifi system&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/eero-Home-WiFi-System-Pack/dp/B00XEW3YD6/sensr-20&#34;&gt;The eero wifi system&lt;/a&gt; is
really quite amazing. It lets you blanket your home in wifi and manage it
with the eero app. You can do lots of neat things, like pause the internet for
different devices or manage the network even when you&amp;rsquo;re not home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally to do port forwarding to your IP camera, you need to configure the camera
to have a specific IP address, then go to the router and add tell it to forward external
ports to the internal ports on that IP address.  eero takes a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to do port forwarding at all, you can simiply use Sensr.net
and have your camera push to Sensr.net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still some reasons you might want to do port forwarding, so here&amp;rsquo;s how it
works with eero:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the eero app, go to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Network Settings &amp;gt; Advanced Settings &amp;gt; Reservations &amp;amp; Port Forwarding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll see a page that lets you add a reservation for your devices. Select
the &lt;strong&gt;+ Add a reservation&lt;/strong&gt; menu.  This will let you choose any of the devices
currently connected to your network.  In my case it was the &lt;em&gt;Balcony Tenvis Camera&lt;/em&gt;
which I wanted to expose on my network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you make a reservation, you can then add port forwarding for that device. In my case
I wanted to forward port 8080 on the outside to port 80 on my camera. This was so a friend
of mine could experiment with my camera remotely. I also forwarded 554 and 660 and you can
see in the screenshot below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:40%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/eero-add-reservation.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;eero app add reservation&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;width:40%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/eero-ip-reservation.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;eero wifi system add port forward&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-port-forwarding&#34;&gt;Why do port forwarding?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally you don&amp;rsquo;t wnat to do port forwarding if you don&amp;rsquo;t have to.  If you want
to see your camera outisde of your network, most cameras now come with apps that
will allow you to view and configure your camera remotely without port forwarding.
These cameras and apps are advertised as P2P enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you could also use &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; which doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any port
forwarding or special firewall configuration. You simply have the cameras push images to
us. You can use Sensr.net &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/10/24/ip-camera-no-firewall-config/&#34;&gt;without any firewall configuration at
all.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s that Tenvis balcony showing our view of Condado. This is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; using any port
forarding at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://sensr.net/javascripts/swfobject.js&#34; type=&#34;text/javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; src=&#34;https://sensr.net/widgets/live_view/16af35cd97/71824&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foscam offline, Why can&#39;t I view my camera live?</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/02/foscam-offline-why-cant-i-view-my-camera-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 09:59:35 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/02/foscam-offline-why-cant-i-view-my-camera-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/foscloud-failed-to-connect.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Cloud Connection Problems&#34;  &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve setup two of the recent Foscam camera models, a Foscam FI9900P and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/ftp-setup-on-the-foscam-wireless-security-camera-1920tvl/&#34;&gt;Foscam
1920TVL&lt;/a&gt;. Both support the Foscam cloud and the setup goes
pretty well. More on that another time. But frequently when I launch the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/foscam/id924381688?mt=8&#34;&gt;Foscam iOS
app&lt;/a&gt; and the cameras are showing as offline when I know that they are
online. How do I know that? I&amp;rsquo;ve connected the cameras to Sensr.net and they continue to upload and show live on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We do support live streams though, so if you&amp;rsquo;re running into the &lt;em&gt;Failed to connect&lt;/em&gt; issue and can&amp;rsquo;t see your camera, try setting up your camera on Sensr.net and viewing the live view through us!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the issue here is that Foscam Cloud is a new service and it&amp;rsquo;s buggy. Maybe they aren&amp;rsquo;t keeping their servers up. Maybe
they aren&amp;rsquo;t monitoring their servers properly? Maybe the great firewall of China is blocking your camera from connecting to
servers over at Big Red. Building a cloud service and keeping it running can be complex, so I hope they are just having growing
pains and will get it sorted soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would you want to use the Foscam Cloud and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; together?  Sensr.net is a pretty simple
DVR in the cloud.  We have lots of cool features but the one thing we can&amp;rsquo;t support is the pan/tilt/zoom that you get
in the Foscam app.  Our service is built on having the cameras upload directly to the Sensr.net servers.  This simiplifies
setup and means you &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/10/24/ip-camera-no-firewall-config/&#34;&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t need any difficult firewall port forwarding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
But it also means we can&amp;rsquo;t support PTZ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have a free trial so you have nothing to loose!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would love to hear your experience with Focam Cloud or Sensr.net, so please leave us a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/foscloud-off.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Cloud Connection Problems&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways To Minimize IoT Vulnerabilities In Your Smart Home Network</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/12/5-ways-to-minimize-iot-vulnerabilities-in-your-smart-home-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 16:35:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/12/5-ways-to-minimize-iot-vulnerabilities-in-your-smart-home-network/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/why-no-open-source-iot-firmware/&#34;&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt; (IoT) is continuing to expand and broaden its own horizons while simultaneously helping to usher people into a
future, which is brimming with all the possibilities that an interconnected world presents. There are many industries that are working to
incorporate the Internet of Things into their infrastructure. One of these industries has been the home security industry and there are many
homeowners who are no proud parents to smart homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smart home is one greatest aspects of the Internet of Things, just because of the sheer number of actions it allows you to complete through
simple commands. For instance, some people can program their homes so that their lights come on as soon as they walk through the door. There are
many benefits to the IoT, from increased efficiency to more comfortable living. However, there are some inherent vulnerabilities in the way the
Internet of Things works, and it is easy to see why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basis of the IoT is that there are several different devices connected to each other on a network, and all sharing information and relaying
data. This concept alone hints at the fact that there are multiple entryways for unauthorized users, as well as security concerns simply because
of the sheer number of interconnected devices. When it comes to homeowners who are using the IoT to power their smart home networks, how can
they minimize these IoT vulnerabilities? LetÕs take a look at some of the ways they can avert this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-proper-password-management&#34;&gt;1. Proper Password Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always best, to begin with, the basics, and one of the basics of great network security is always making sure that you are properly
managing the passwords that grant devices access to your network. The first step to proper password management is to ensure that you create
unique passwords for each of the devices that you have connected to your smart home network. In addition to this, it is best to make sure that
you change these passwords on a regular basis so that you are consistently reducing the possibility of anyone discovering them. There are many
homeowners who overlook this simple method, but it goes a long way to help keep your network secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-utilize-a-secure-firewall&#34;&gt;2. Utilize a secure Firewall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important for homeowners to realize how vulnerable their networks can be if they do not provide any form of protection. One of the best
forms of protection comes in the form of a secure firewall. It is not a smart idea to leave your network protected by a simple router.
Homeowners should invest in secure firewalls that act as safeguards to every accessible endpoint that exists on their network. Firewalls exist
to help protect your network from unauthorized access and they greatly reduce the chances of anyone successfully &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/is-your-security-camera-hacking-someone-else/&#34;&gt;hacking into your smart home
network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-security-software-updates&#34;&gt;3. Security Software Updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing software updates is quite similar to proper password management. This is because the brunt of the responsibility falls on the homeowner
to be attentive. It is important that you constantly check to see if there are software updates available for the devices that you have on your
smart home network. These software updates are an important part of ensuring that your devices continue to run smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases, manufacturers might have discovered a flaw in the device and then release a software patch meant to rectify said problem. If the
user does not take advantage of these software patches, they will most likely end up having severe network flaws and holes that a hacker can
take advantage of to gain access to their network. One of the best ways to manage security software updates is to set at least 3 monthly
reminders. That way you never fall into the trap of forgetting that you need to update your security software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-disable-additional-features&#34;&gt;4. Disable additional features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this is something that many homeowners tend to overlook, simply because they do not know this might increase the chances of their network
being made vulnerable. In most cases, smart devices have additional features that grant them access to the networks at different times without
necessarily having to go through any security verification or authorization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process makes your entire network extremely vulnerable because it gives hackers the opportunity to exploit these loopholes. When you are
setting up your smart home network, it is imperative that you identify the additional features that each device might use. If there are any that
leave your network open and accessible, make sure that you disable these features. Essentially, you want to make it as hard as possible for a
hacker to gain access to your network. The most efficient way to do this is to plug up all possible access points that could end up being taken
advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-private-network&#34;&gt;5. Private Network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things is a network of interconnected devices. It is not really a shock that this might seem lucrative to hackers. However, an
additional way to minimize the flaws of an IoT network in the smart home is to utilize private networks. The use of a private network will add
an additional layer of security for your IoT devices. Also, it is always best to keep the network that functions with your IoT devices separate
from other networks so that they do not compromise each other with the amount of data that is being transmitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IoT on a smart home network really changes the way a home can operate, and it increases the amount of possible things that any homeowner can
accomplish. The benefits of the IoT are very likely endless, as we are only just scratching the surface. However, there are some vulnerabilities
that exist, much like anything else, so it is crucial for homeowners to make sure that they are safe guarding themselves against any of these
vulnerabilities. You may think that this is a high level of paranoia, but it is important to remember that if someone is able to gain access to
one device on an IoT network, they will most likely gain access to your entire network simply by piggybacking off of the compromised device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steps mentioned above will help keep your smart home network safe, but do not forget that physical security also plays an important role in
stemming inherent network vulnerabilities. As a homeowner, make sure that you discuss your home security with a security professional or a
residential locksmith, they will be able to help you with &lt;a href=&#34;http://united-locksmith.net/home-locksmith/smart-lock-installation&#34;&gt;smart lock installations&lt;/a&gt; as well as help you keep your home safe and secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;author-bio&#34;&gt;Author Bio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ralph Goodman is a professional writer and the resident expert on locks and security over at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://united-locksmith.net/blog&#34;&gt;Lock Blog&lt;/a&gt;. The Lock Blog is a great
resource to learn about keys, locks and safety. They offer tips, advice and how-to&amp;rsquo;s for consumers, locksmiths, and security professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfa R36 AWUS036NH Network Scan Not Working</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/12/alfa-r36-awus036nh-network-scan-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 10:13:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/12/alfa-r36-awus036nh-network-scan-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfa.com.tw/download_show.php?combo_0=11&amp;amp;combo_1=R36&amp;amp;combo_2=Firmware&amp;amp;k&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/R36FirmwareVersions.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;R36 Firmware Versions&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you having problems with your &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Alfa-R36-Repeater-Extender-AWUS036H/dp/B004ZF0I3U/sensr-20&#34;&gt;Alfa R36&lt;/a&gt; not being able
to scan for networks? If the firmware version on your R36 needs to be at least 1.2.1.2 or it won&amp;rsquo;t work with the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Alfa-AWUSO36NH-Wireless-Long-Rang-Network/dp/B0035APGP6/sensr-20&#34;&gt;AWUS036NH&lt;/a&gt;. See the screen shot above. At first I
didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that I had a different version of the AWUS036NH, the version that has an H at the end: AWUS036NH not AWUS036N. They are
different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the firmware upgrade everything works great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfa.com.tw/download_show.php?combo_0=11&amp;amp;combo_1=R36&amp;amp;combo_2=Firmware&amp;amp;k&#34;&gt;firmware here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-this-for&#34;&gt;What is this for?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/AlfaDevices.jpg&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;R36 and AWUS036NH&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Alfa-R36-Repeater-Extender-AWUS036H/dp/B004ZF0I3U/sensr-20&#34;&gt;Alfa R36&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Alfa-AWUSO36NH-Wireless-Long-Rang-Network/dp/B0035APGP6/sensr-20&#34;&gt;AWUS036NH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use the R36 and the AWUS036NH to create your own hotspot out of another wifi network. The AWUS036NH is essentially an antennae.
The R36 is a router that also creates it&amp;rsquo;s own wifi network. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a bunch of devices in your RV or boat.  You can connect
them all to the R36&amp;rsquo;s wifi network.  Then when you park in the Starbucks parking lot, you can tell the R36 to use the Starbucks wifi
and all of your devices on your local network will connect to the world on over the Starbucks network.  You could have security cameras
and laptops and wireless printers all connected to your R36.  Thus you&amp;rsquo;ll have to &lt;em&gt;scan for networks&lt;/em&gt; whenever you change locations, but
at least you won&amp;rsquo;t need to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have yours working, you might want to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.rokland.com/blogs/news/6547671-how-to-optimize-your-alfa-r36-router&#34;&gt;this article on optimizing your R36&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;record-your-ip-camera-on-sensr-net&#34;&gt;Record your IP camera on Sensr.net&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you get your R36 working, go get some security cameras and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;connect them to Sensr.net!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FTP Setup on the Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/ftp-setup-on-the-foscam-wireless-security-camera-1920tvl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 11:36:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/ftp-setup-on-the-foscam-wireless-security-camera-1920tvl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- 
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/foscamr2.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
 --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:25%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/foscamr2.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;width:60%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamBox.jpg&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;foscam-r2-2mp-1080p-hd-wireless-security-camera&#34;&gt;Foscam R2 2MP 1080P HD Wireless Security Camera&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Foscam-Wireless-Security-Camera-1920TVL/dp/B01DJ1FTTS/sensr-20&#34;&gt;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&lt;/a&gt; is the
latest slim model from Foscam, also called the R2 it seems. I just opened this one yesterday and Foscam seems to be upping their game.
The box is much nicer than they used in the previous models. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit more like the Apple experience. Not bad for a $70 product!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera works well with Sensr.net, so you can use our cloud DVR service with the Foscam.  We have a free trial, so sign up and follow the instructions below on how to get it working with Sensr.net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;it-speaks&#34;&gt;It speaks!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera is easy to setup using the Foscam app.  As a nice bonus they have added audio cues that come from the camera.  It says &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Hello Foscam&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; when it powers up. Its little head rotates around and the camera said &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ethernet connection succeeded&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.  Later
after I setup the wifi, it said &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wireless connection succeeded&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.  I have to admit this is a nice feature. No more wondering if the
camera connected to the network or not.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I want the audio piping up when the power goes off and back on though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;interesting-features-in-the-foscam-app&#34;&gt;Interesting Features in the Foscam App&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/foscam/id924381688?mt=8&#34;&gt;Foscam app&lt;/a&gt; mostly seems to work. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s filled with grammatical mistakes.
It let&amp;rsquo;s you share the images on &lt;strong&gt;WeChat&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;WeChat Moments&lt;/strong&gt;, whatever that is. (Ok, it&amp;rsquo;s the Facebook &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wechat.com/en/&#34;&gt;Messenger of
China&lt;/a&gt;, but not really very important to the non-Chinese market.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:30%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamAmerica.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Country selection Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;width:30%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamWechat.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wechat Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;width:30%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamFirmware.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Firware upgrade Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a selection for United States but you can select &lt;em&gt;America&lt;/em&gt; which is kind of cute.  I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure they mean France
not French, but maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a language selector as well as a location selector?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe the best new feature is that you can upgrade the firmware in the app! Excellent! Now when there is a security issue in the firmware, the
app will make it simple to perform the upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-s-missing&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s missing?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Foscam R2 2MP 1080P HD Wireless Security Camera has a lot of controls but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the local IP address for the camera. If you&amp;rsquo;re going to setup this camera for FTP you&amp;rsquo;ll need to
find it&amp;rsquo;s IP address. Normally I would recommend connecting to your router and looking for the device with a matching MAC address. This will
work if you&amp;rsquo;re using the wired connection. The MAC address is printed on the bottom of the camera. However, the wireless MAC address is not.
It would be nice if the app would tell you the URL to connect to the web interface. If you&amp;rsquo;ve already put your amera on wifi, you can still
find it but you may have to try connecting to a bunch of different IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;port-88&#34;&gt;Port 88!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to connect to the camera, make sure to use port 88. For some reason the default port for Foscam is 88. That means you&amp;rsquo;ll have
to go to &lt;code&gt;http://IP:88/&lt;/code&gt; to get to the web interface. For example, if your camera&amp;rsquo;s IP is &lt;code&gt;172.16.20.73&lt;/code&gt; you&amp;rsquo;ll need to go to
&lt;code&gt;http://172.16.20.73:88/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;safari-plugins&#34;&gt;Safari Plugins!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using a Mac, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install plugins.  I really wish these camera manufacturers would just use web standards instead
of making us install software.  I tried configuring the camera without the plugins, but it really seems to enforce this.  Maybe future
versions of the app will support FTP configuration so we can skip the browser all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;configure-the-ftp-server&#34;&gt;Configure the FTP Server&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Log on to your account at &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; and click the add camera button. This will give you the three pieces of information
you need to configure your camera: server, username, and password. Our server names are &lt;code&gt;f0.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt; through &lt;code&gt;f9.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt;. The usernames
are &lt;code&gt;camNNN&lt;/code&gt; where &lt;code&gt;NNN&lt;/code&gt; is an integer. The password is generated randomly. Be careful since in a password some characters can be confused.
Zeros and Os looks alike. Ones and Ls also look alike. It&amp;rsquo;s best to copy and paste the passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have these, you can then go to the FTP sever page on the camera, which looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamFTPSettings.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FTP server URL shows a dir at the end. On the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; side we just ignore this. You can add it if you wish but it&amp;rsquo;s
not needed. Your URL should start with FTP though, like this: &lt;code&gt;ftp://fX.sensr.net/&lt;/code&gt;, where X is the server that
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; tells you to use for your camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;configure-snapshot-settings&#34;&gt;Configure Snapshot Settings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you&amp;rsquo;ll want to configure the snapshot settings, which tells the camera to upload JPEG snapshots to &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;. We
recommend you send an image per second to our servers. (See &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/10/24/ip-camera-no-firewall-config/&#34;&gt;No Firewall Config&lt;/a&gt; for more details
on why we recommend this.) This way we can generate a live Motion JPEG stream (MJPEG) on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; site. Make sure to
select all in the upper left hand corner of the schedule so the camera will always upload. If you don&amp;rsquo;t want us to process images on certain
days or certain hours, this is the place to configure that. Make sure to click the Save button at the top. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve done this your Foscam
should start uploading to &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamSnapshotSettings.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; side the page should go from this:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-s3.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt; Waiting for upload&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To a page that shows the image your camera uploaded.  Something like this:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2013/12/sensr-add-camera-success.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Success!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, now you&amp;rsquo;re done with the camera config. Your camera is now on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ll archive all the motion
events, giving you 30 days of archives, SMS and email alerts, guest access, and a whole lot more.  You can view the live stream on our website
or in our apps. No firewall configuration is needed. No PC in the basement required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any problems, send email to info @ sensr.net and we&amp;rsquo;ll try to help you out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;don-t-set-scheduled-recording&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Set Scheduled Recording&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be tempted to set the Scheduled Recording.  This is for MKV video files.  If you upload those to Sensr.net we&amp;rsquo;ll just remove
them, since we only support JPEG files right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/UnsetFoscamScheduledRecording.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;don-t-set-motion-detection-settings&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Set Motion Detection Settings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also don&amp;rsquo;t need the motion detection settings to work with Sensr.net.  We do the motion detection on the server side.
See our blog post &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2011/07/25/true-meaning-of-motion-detection-off/&#34;&gt;The True Meaning of Motion Detection Off&lt;/a&gt;
for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FoscamMotionDetectionSettings.png&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Foscam Wireless Security Camera 1920TVL&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;shodan-fun&#34;&gt;Shodan Fun&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The built in web server seems to be lighttpd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the headers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTTP/1.1 200 OK
Content-Type: text/html
Accept-Ranges: bytes
ETag: &amp;quot;18210424&amp;quot;
Last-Modified: Thu, 28 Jul 2016 03:47:34 GMT
Content-Length: 38561
Date: Thu, 01 Dec 2016 12:08:20 GMT
Server: lighttpd/1.4.31
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scan on shodan.io for the etag &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shodan.io/search?query=ETag%3A+%2218210424%22&#34;&gt;finds a few cameras&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hikvision FTP Server IP address leads to Zombie Apocalypse</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/hikvision-ftp-server-ip-address-leads-to-zombie-apocalypse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 21:59:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/11/hikvision-ftp-server-ip-address-leads-to-zombie-apocalypse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/zombie-ip-camera.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Never give up!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Ok, these &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Hikvision-DS-2CD2042WD-I-Network-English-Security/dp/B01DIKF4XG/sensr-20&#34;&gt;Hikvision cameras&lt;/a&gt; are pretty nice
and seem like great quality for the price.  However, I have one major issue with them, they
don&amp;rsquo;t let you use hostnames for the FTP server.  You have to use an IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Hikvision-DS-2CD2042WD-I-Network-English-Security/dp/B01DIKF4XG/sensr-20&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/DS-2CD2042WD-I.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Hikvision DS-2CD2042WD-I Bullet Camera&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/hikvision-ftp-setup.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Hikvision FTP Setup&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Why would they require this?  I suppose for most cameras connect to a server on the local network, thus it won&amp;rsquo;t have a DNS name
anyway, why not just require an IP address? It means that when the camera does connect to the FTP server, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to do
a DNS lookup, but that seems like a pretty big trade off. You have to hardwire the IP address into the camera config.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-external-servers&#34;&gt;What about external servers?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you require an IP address, then you need to find the IP address of the server. At &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; we run FTP servers and we
use hostnames like &lt;code&gt;f0.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt;. If you want to use the Hikvision with our service, you need to connect to one of our servers (currently f0 through f9).
But to use the Hikvision, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to find out the IP address of our servers.  In the case of &lt;code&gt;f9.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt; you can run &lt;code&gt;nslookup&lt;/code&gt; like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ nslookup f9.sensr.net
Server:		8.8.8.8
Address:	8.8.8.8#53

Non-authoritative answer:
Name:	f9.sensr.net
Address: 74.207.245.42
Name:	f9.sensr.net
Address: 96.126.101.33
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, notice that it returns two different answers.  At Sensr.net we (currently) have two servers that serve as &lt;code&gt;f9.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt;.  We do this
for redundancy.  If one of our servers fails, then the other one can take over for it.  Of course this redundancy won&amp;rsquo;t help you
if you hard wire the IP address.  For the Hikvision, just pick one or the other IP addresses and it should work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-loadbalancing-and-failover&#34;&gt;What about loadbalancing and failover?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of screws up our load balancing and failover.  But at least it works.  However, it only works as long as our servers keep the same IP
address.  What if we upgrade or move a server?  It&amp;rsquo;s IP address will change and your camera won&amp;rsquo;t work anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maybe-security-could-be-compromised-too&#34;&gt;Maybe security could be compromised too&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use servers at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linode.com&#34;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; and we might decide to upgrade and get a bigger server at Linode,
or maybe move to &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt; or even &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Cloud&lt;/a&gt;. In that case,
the IP address that we used to use will get deprecated.  This probably means your camera will stop working.  But it could mean that it starts
uploading to a server that isn&amp;rsquo;t part of Sensr.net!  Let&amp;rsquo;s say we drop the server at Linode, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty likely that Linode will re-use that IP
address for someone else.  That new owner might notice that there are cameras trying to connect to it.  That new owner might also decide to let
those cameras connect and then they could start collecting images that are uploaded by your cameras.  Hmm, that seems like a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-serious-is-this&#34;&gt;How serious is this?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we have changed the IP addresses of our upload servers once in 6 years.  So it doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen often.  However, we are working on a
major change and I expect the IP addresses will change in the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-can-we-do-to-help&#34;&gt;What can we do to help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we change servers and drop the IP addresses for these machines,
we can move over the DNS names (&lt;code&gt;f0.sensr.net .. f9.sensr.net&lt;/code&gt;) and see what cameras continue to connect. If all the cameras move over (they won&amp;rsquo;t)
then we don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be cameras left connecting to the old IP addresses.  In this case we can warn our users that they need
to update their cameras.  We&amp;rsquo;ll probably send out an email and give our users some time to make the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;zombie-cameras&#34;&gt;Zombie cameras&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/zombiecam.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Never give up!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We have quite a few zombie cameras trying to connect to our servers.  Zombies are cameras that used to work with the service, but no longer
are on paid accounts.  This means we don&amp;rsquo;t let them upload images, their logins fail.  But most zombies keep plugging away,  mindlessly attempting
to upload to our servers even though we won&amp;rsquo;t let them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of these cameras, we may not be able to contact the owners, so after we finally decomission the servers, they may end up connecting to
some new server deployed at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linode.com&#34;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt;. If the owner of that new server decides to let the zombie connect, they could end up collecting
lots of potentially private images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iot-gone-mad&#34;&gt;IoT gone mad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one example of how the IoT world is leading to unintended consequences.  People setup cameras so they can be more secure, but
through a sequence of perfectly normal events they end up with something they don&amp;rsquo;t expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll ask Linode if they will decommission those IP addresses.  Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll just keep paying for them.  One thing is for sure, we will
warn users before we release the IP addresses back into the pool.  We&amp;rsquo;ll keep track of how much upload traffic we get to our deprecated
servers.  It might lead to another interesting blog post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned, the Zombie Apocalypse is far from over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shameless-plug&#34;&gt;Shameless plug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re still not afraid of the zombies, we would love to have you as a customer. &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;Point your IP camera at us&lt;/a&gt; and we&amp;rsquo;ll do some useful stuff with what you send us. We have a free trial, so it won&amp;rsquo;t cost you anything.  If you decide not to stick with us, please
delete our FTP server from your camera. It will be as satisfying as shooting a zombie in the head!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why no open source IoT Firmware?</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/why-no-open-source-iot-firmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 20:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/why-no-open-source-iot-firmware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Dans les entrailles urbaines / In the urban bowels&#34; href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/m43photos/12239139316/in/photolist-jDwMHo-cxs18J-fAiNqu-dgqBrp-8JiYae-zJCUs-5hmBet-ciyJEf-aqSgjf-4zhcab-e6MK4D-3dqLhP-qP2FY-9u9Vmd-aqrFT2-6F34w2-5NAo8e-5M2nnt-cxt85q-2zrJy9-7aUP9A-5NEEK7-deB66G-bEtv1q-dksYJC-c7gy4E-rU8r9v-5S8j7P-bToeAP-6F7cKq-5NEEMf-6F7d5b-dNifDu-3bsbWr-6F7cUA-5NAoan-5NEEfh-ckh731-5NAod6-sNL1k-8DkNxR-skKu3-sGNzi-8B9Dfe-4Poqgd-cv5hA5-cvgpHu-iH8cKJ-jSg8jZ-dgSE9g&#34; data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5524/12239139316_6e97104ce8_k.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dans les entrailles urbaines / In the urban bowels&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;334&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IoT (Internet of Things) is taking off. We&amp;rsquo;re coming up with all kinds of internet connected devices. Many of these devices are simply computers with interesting sensors and controllers attached. At Sensr.net we think mostly about IP cameras, which are a specific kind of IoT device. But that &lt;a href=&#34;https://nest.com/thermostat/meet-nest-thermostat/&#34; title=&#34;Nest Thermostat&#34;&gt;Nest thermostat&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Echo-Bluetooth-Speaker-with-WiFi-Alexa/dp/B00X4WHP5E&#34; title=&#34;Amazon Echo&#34;&gt;Amazon Echo speaker&lt;/a&gt; are also examples of IoT devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days most IP cameras will connect to your internet via WiFi or Ethernet and allow you to view and control the camera remotely. Many of these cameras include a P2P (peer to peer) feature that allows you to view the camera directly even if you don&amp;rsquo;t open your firewall. This is a neat trick which is accomplished by having the camera keep open a connection back to some well known server. When you want to connect to your camera, you&amp;rsquo;re really connecting to some remote server (in China maybe?) that then does some network magic (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/STUN&#34; title=&#34;STUN: Session Traversal Utilities for NAT&#34;&gt;STUN&lt;/a&gt;) and lets your smartphone app connect to your camera through your firewall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That nice P2P feature is pretty great, but it also means that there are servers out there on the net that can get inside your home network. Where are those servers running? Who&amp;rsquo;s job is it to make sure they are secure? Who has access to those servers and thus your network and even your cameras?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-your-cams-are-belong-to-us&#34;&gt;All your cams are belong to us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Mostly we&amp;rsquo;re pretty cavalier about connecting cool new gadgets to our networks. Maybe we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be. It seems like there ought to be some way to make sure the devices you trust are actually trustworthy. How can we be sure that our security cameras are actually secure? (Warning: &lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2016/10/19/is-your-security-camera-hacking-someone-else/&#34; title=&#34;Cameras hacked into botnets&#34;&gt;They probably aren&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truthiness-in-our-firmware&#34;&gt;Truthiness in our firmware?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these devices run an operating system of some kind embedded down in their firmware. What if we created an open source firmware that we could trust? We could buy fun cheap hardware from our friends in China but then install our own good old open source code on that hardware instead of trusting the glop that came on it. Don&amp;rsquo;t want your camera connecting out some potentially compromised P2P jumphost somewhere? No problem! Just install your own firmware and configure your own jumphost or maybe one run by a company you trust. (This could be a new business opportunity for &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net: Watch your stuff!&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; maybe&amp;#8230;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-say-tomato-6-8230&#34;&gt;You say &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tomato_(firmware)&#34; title=&#34;Tomato Firmware&#34;&gt;tomato&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one successful example of this, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dd-wrt.com/site/index&#34; title=&#34;DD-WRT Site&#34;&gt;DD-WRT software&lt;/a&gt; that runs on a large number of routers.  There are a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_router_firmware_projects&#34; title=&#34;Router Firmware&#34;&gt;open source firmwares&lt;/a&gt; out there. Why can&amp;rsquo;t we have one for cameras? Or more generally IoT devices?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-together-now&#34;&gt;All together now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in joining an effort along these lines, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@sensr.net?Subject=Open%20firmware&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;drop me an email&lt;/a&gt; or contribute to the project on Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sensrnet/sensros&#34; title=&#34;SensrOS: Open source IP Camera Firmware&#34;&gt;https://github.com/sensrnet/sensros&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of cool things that could be built into this firmware.  Imagine the machine learning projects or advanced image recognition that could be built into something like this. More basic things could be done too, like reference designs for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onvif.org/&#34; title=&#34;ONVIF&#34;&gt;ONVIF&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psialliance.org/&#34; title=&#34;Physical Security Interoperability Alliance&#34;&gt;PSIA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is your security camera hacking someone else?</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/is-your-security-camera-hacking-someone-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 18:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/10/19/is-your-security-camera-hacking-someone-else/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3207&#34; style=&#34;width: 768px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3207&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/2016/10/wsjscreenshot-1024x5741.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Who watches the watchers?&#34; width=&#34;758&#34; height=&#34;562&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 758px) 100vw, 758px&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Who watches the watchers?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month the Wall Street Journal reported: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wsj.com/articles/hackers-infect-army-of-cameras-dvrs-for-massive-internet-attacks-1475179428&#34;&gt;Hackers Infect Army of Cameras, DVRs for Massive Internet Attacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can something like this happen?  It turns out security cameras and DVRs are just network connected computers, and they can be hacked just like any other computer.  However, it&amp;#8217;s worse than that, a large number of these systems ship with default passwords, so anyone who can connect to them can get into the system and install any software they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net: Watch your stuff &#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; you can add an extra layer of security to your IP camera deployments.
&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-my-firewall&#34;&gt;What about my firewall?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait, what does it matter that there are default passwords on these systems?  These devices are normally behind a firewall, right?  Maybe, but most DVRs and IP cameras are configured so you can view and configure them from outside your firewall.  When these systems are installed, most of them instruct you to set up port forwarding.  This is where you can get into trouble.  If you configure your firewall for port forwarding, you&amp;#8217;re allowing anyone on the internet to connect to your device.  If you setup port forwarding but don&amp;#8217;t bother to change the default passwords, then you&amp;#8217;re asking for trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-are-your-own-it-guy&#34;&gt;You are your own IT guy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do setup port forwarding, make sure you change all the default passwords and keep your firmware up to date.  Yes, this is a hassle.  Updating firmware on wireless security cameras is error prone and confusing.  You have to make sure you have the right firmware for your camera.  Sometimes there are slightly different hardware versions and if you install the wrong firmware on the wrong hardware, you&amp;#8217;ll brick your device.  Another hassle is that most manufacturers insist that you do the upgrade over a wired connection.  This sounds easy until you realize that the camera is mounted somewhere and now you have to get your toolbox and a ladder just to upgrade your firmware.  No wonder these devices are not getting updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-sensr-net-help&#34;&gt;Can Sensr.net help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34; title=&#34;Sensr.net: Watch your stuff &#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; doesn&amp;#8217;t require port forwarding (cameras push to our servers, nothing reaches back into your network).  This means if you&amp;#8217;re using security cameras or network attached DVRs don&amp;#8217;t need to be accessible from the internet at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;try-sensr-net-for-free&#34;&gt;Try Sensr.net for free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an IP camera, give us a try.  Sign up for our &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;one week free trial&lt;/a&gt;, no credit card required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legally Monitor your Airbnb with cheap Sensr.net security cameras</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/09/27/legally-monitor-your-airbnb-with-cheap-sensr-net-security-cameras/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 01:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/09/27/legally-monitor-your-airbnb-with-cheap-sensr-net-security-cameras/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been renting our place on &lt;a title=&#34;Airbnb&#34; href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; for about a year now and it&amp;rsquo;s been great to have &lt;a title=&#34;Sensr.net&#34; href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; cameras monitoring our place while we aren&amp;rsquo;t there. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, we don&amp;rsquo;t have cameras &lt;em&gt;inside the private spaces of our home&lt;/em&gt;, we have exterior cameras that monitor the approaches to the house. Think &lt;strong&gt;Driveway Camera&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Front Door Camera,&lt;/strong&gt; etc. We only monitor the &lt;em&gt;public spaces&lt;/em&gt; around our home, with &lt;em&gt;one exception&lt;/em&gt;: owner only spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;don-t-go-there&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Go There&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we rent our home on Airbnb we close off a handful of rooms, like the home office, garage, and basement storage rooms. We &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; have cameras in these spaces, where we &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t allow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; the Airbnb guest to go. These cameras are behind locked doors and should never record the guests unless they have picked the locks to get into the rooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;party-zone&#34;&gt;Party Zone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External cameras are great in letting you know when or if the guest arrived and if the correct number of guests arrived. Our home has a strict &amp;#8216;no parties&amp;rsquo; rule. We have found this violated a couple of times and it was obvious from the cameras that more than the max 8 guests were staying at the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;neighbor-friendly&#34;&gt;Neighbor Friendly&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We share a driveway with our neighbors, and we make it very clear to our Airbnb guests that they are not to use the driveway.  This didn&amp;rsquo;t really work the first few times, but after we added &lt;em&gt;You will be fined for using the driveway&lt;/em&gt; to the directions with an additional &lt;em&gt;The driveway is monitor by security cameras&lt;/em&gt; this problem went away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;external-cameras&#34;&gt;External Cameras&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding external cameras can be more difficult than adding an internal wifi camera.  There are lots of great solutions, and if you can run a wire to the location where you want the camera, a POE (Power Over Ethernet) camera can be a great solution.  You only need to run one wire but you need a special router that can also send power.  If you live in a temperate climate, you might try &lt;a title=&#34;HOWTO Make a Cheap Network Camera Enclosure&#34; href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2011/05/26/howto-make-cheap-network-camera-enclosure/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this cheap camera cover solution&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;internal-cameras&#34;&gt;Internal Cameras&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internal cameras are pretty easy to setup and there are thousands of models to choose from.  Generally these are cheap and work with your wifi.  You only need a power outlet and access to your wifi.  Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a title=&#34;How to Setup the TENVIS IPROBOT3 with Cloud recording&#34; href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2014/07/03/how-to-setup-the-tenvis-iprobot3-with-cloud-recording/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tenvis&lt;/a&gt; PTZ (pan, tilt, zoom) cameras.  I use their live viewing app to view the camera and change it&amp;rsquo;s positioning.  I use Sensr.net for recording, alerts, and sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;share-the-fun&#34;&gt;Share the Fun&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a friend who keeps an eye on our home when we aren&amp;rsquo;t around.  With Sensr.net it&amp;rsquo;s easy to give him access to the exterior cameras.  When you have a camera on Sensr.net, you can give other&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a title=&#34;Guest Access for Sensr.net Cameras&#34; href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2012/04/11/guest-access-for-sensr-net-cameras/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;guest access to those cameras&lt;/a&gt;.  He helps out when we&amp;rsquo;re not around and manages the cleaning crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cost-effective&#34;&gt;Cost Effective&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Sensr.net you can use almost any camera.  If your camera can upload JPEG images with FTP (like 98% of all security cameras), then it will work with Sensr.net.  We don&amp;rsquo;t sell cameras, so we&amp;rsquo;re _camera agnostic.  _You could even make your own camera with a Raspberry Pi and a USB cam and it would work with Sensr.net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-notified&#34;&gt;Get Notified&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Sensr.net not only do we record in the cloud, but we can send you alerts when we detect motion.  This works great for the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;owner only&lt;/em&gt; spaces.&lt;/strong&gt;  If you have a camera setup in your private space, you&amp;rsquo;ll appreciate a SMS or email when something starts moving around in there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;free-trial&#34;&gt;Free Trial!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re an Airbnb host, you can give this a try for free.  If you&amp;rsquo;re not an Airbnb host, you can try it out too!  We have a one week free trial.  Grab a camera and give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warning: setting up an IP camera can be a bit complex.  If you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable setting up a wifi router, then you&amp;rsquo;ll probably be fine.  One big advantage to using Sensr.net is that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do any &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/10/24/ip-camera-no-firewall-config/&#34; title=&#34;View IP Camera Remotely, No Firewall Config&#34;&gt;port forwarding or complex firewall rules&lt;/a&gt;, so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit easier than you might expect if you&amp;rsquo;ve tried this kind of thing in the past.  If you get stuck, just drop us an email at support@sensr.net and we&amp;rsquo;ll give you a hand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensr.net Security Camera Offline</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/02/29/security-camera-offline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 13:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/02/29/security-camera-offline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sensr.net shows cameras as offline if they haven&amp;rsquo;t uploaded an image in the last 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does this happen? We recommend that you have your camera upload images continuously to Sensr.net at 1 or 2 snapshots per second. This way you can view the live stream on our site &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/10/24/ip-camera-no-firewall-config/&#34; title=&#34;View IP Camera Remotely, No Firewall Config&#34;&gt;without opening your firewall&lt;/a&gt;. If you have your camera set to only upload images on motion, then when there is no motion, we&amp;rsquo;ll show your camera as offline.  See this post about &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2011/07/25/true-meaning-of-motion-detection-off/&#34; title=&#34;True meaning of motion detection off&#34;&gt;configuring cameras with motion detection&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Camera Archiving and Clip Download</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/02/28/security-camera-archiving-and-clip-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 13:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2016/02/28/security-camera-archiving-and-clip-download/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With your Sensr.net account,  we save images for one month on our site. Images are deleted when they are 32 days old. If you want to keep the images longer just save them as favorites or make a clip. Favorites and clips are kept until you delete the camera from our service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;a href=&#34;http://sensr.net/blog/2014/04/29/making-clips-on-sensr-net/&#34; title=&#34;Making Clips on Sensr.net&#34;&gt;make a clip&lt;/a&gt;, we will generate an mpeg file and send you a link to download it. The link we send is good for 30 days.  Make sure your login email is correct and check your spam folder if you don&amp;rsquo;t see the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re working on some programs that will allow you to pull down images to your local hard drive. See the open source project here.  If you&amp;rsquo;re a coder, give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adamb/Sensr-utils&#34; title=&#34;Sensr Utils&#34;&gt;https://github.com/adamb/Sensr-utils&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>