<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud Dvr on Sensr.net Blog | Watch your Stuff!</title>
    <link>http://blog.sensr.net/tags/cloud-dvr/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud Dvr on Sensr.net Blog | Watch your Stuff!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.sensr.net/tags/cloud-dvr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to configure a Wansview Full HD Waterproof Camera NCM751GA</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/07/how-to-configure-a-wansview-full-hd-waterproof-camera-ncm751ga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 09:00:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/07/how-to-configure-a-wansview-full-hd-waterproof-camera-ncm751ga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/WanCam.png&#34; title=&#34;Wansview Full HD Waterproof Camera NCM751GA&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wansview NCM751GA is an outdoor HD camera licensed by Wansview and manufactured by Shenzhen Smarteye Digital Electronics. It’s listed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Wansview-Outdoor-Wireless-Security-Waterproof/dp/B01AC5DI8I/sensr-20&#34;&gt;Amazon for about $75&lt;/a&gt;.
 One of the biggest problems with this camera is that it’ll only send images through FTP when either motion is detected or one of the sensors is
tripped. This means that when you configure it with Sensr.net, it will only upload images when the aforementioned conditions are met. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2011/07/25/true-meaning-of-motion-detection-off/&#34;&gt;Turning
off Sensr’s motion detection&lt;/a&gt; when using this camera is recommended .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/WansviewPluggedIn.JPG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you start, you’ll want to plug your camera into an outlet. The red light on the power brick tells you that power is going to the camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/iSVPApp.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, use your phone to download the free iSmartviewPro app. If you’re not using an iPhone, the app is available for Android as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/MainMenu.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the app is finished installing, go ahead and open it. You should see a menu that looks like this. Make sure your camera is in arm’s reach and press the Add Camera button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/AddCam.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll be brought to this screen. Tap the “Add cameras via WiFi configuration guide” button&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:25%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/QRScan.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width:59%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/QRSticker.JPG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app will then ask you to scan the camera’s QR code. On the bottom of your camera, there’s a sticker with this QR code. Make sure you have your phone ready before pressing the blue button. This will open your phone’s camera; use it to focus on the QR code and the app will automatically scan it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/GiveCamName.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, name your camera and login with the default Username and Password. The default username is “admin” and the default password is “123456”. For security, you should change these after you’re done setting up your camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/WifiPassEmpty.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter your wifi name and password and press next. Ensure you don’t have any headphones or bluetooth devices connected to your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/CamConfig.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure your phone is close to your camera and the volume is on. The app will play a sound. Wait until you’re brought back to the main screen of the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:50%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/Finished2.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your camera is now set up with the iSmartviewPro app! If you don’t want to connect this camera to Sensr, then at this point you’re finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;connecting-to-sensr-net&#34;&gt;Connecting to Sensr.net&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:49%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/EditCamera.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width:49%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/AdvSettings.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the home screen, tap the little arrow left of the camera you just set up. You’ll be brought to a screen similar to the one above (left). You can change the username/password from here. Press the Advanced Settings button, and you should see a screen that looks like the image above (right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:49%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/AlarmSettings.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width:49%&#34; src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/FTPSettings.PNG&#34; class=&#34;img-rounded&#34; alt=&#34;Wansview Plugged In&#34; align=&#34;middle&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go into Alarm Settings and ensure that Motion Detect is armed and that Save Picture on the FTP is enabled. On a computer, log into your Sensr.net account and click the add camera button. You’ll be given a server name, username, and password. These are your FTP credentials. On your phone, navigate to Advanced Settings in the iSmartviewpro app, then tap FTP Setting. Copy your Sensr.net FTP credentials into the app, then hit done. Once you’ve done that, your camera should be connected with Sensr.net! Remember that this model only uploads images when motion detection is tripped, so if you see that the camera isn’t uploading images to Sensr.net, wave your hand in front of the lens a couple of times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Alternative to Blink Security Cam</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/05/an-alternative-to-blink-security-cam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 09:00:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/05/an-alternative-to-blink-security-cam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/BlinkCamera.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Blink 	Indoor HD Camera&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;While Blink may be easy to setup and use, there are a number of drawbacks to using Blink’s service that might tempt you to try
an alternative like Sensr.net. Here are some reasons that you might want to try Sensr.net instead of Blink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheaper Cameras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not exclusively battery power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More cloud storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than 2 types of cameras available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APIs for accessing your footage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in using Sensr.net as an alternative to using Blink, give us a try. We have a free trial of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;device-cost&#34;&gt;Device Cost&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cheapest bundle that Blink offers is their &lt;a href=&#34;https://blinkforhome.com/collections/blink-security-camera&#34;&gt;indoor package&lt;/a&gt;,
which starts at $99. If you opt for their &lt;a href=&#34;https://blinkforhome.com/pages/blink-xt-outdoor-cameras&#34;&gt;weatherproof package&lt;/a&gt;
instead, you’ll have to pay $129. Sensr.net’s cloud service is compatible with nearly all IP cameras, some of which come as
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/DIGOO-Security-Surveillance-115-Wide-Angle-Detection/dp/B06X3R1H5M/sensr-20&#34;&gt;cheap as $25&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;power-options&#34;&gt;Power Options&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/Electric_batteries.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Blink Batteries&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Blink’s cameras exclusively use battery power. Battery powered cameras can be placed almost anywhere, since they don’t have to
be plugged into an outlet. However, these batteries must be replaced every so often, or the camera will turn off. But what if
you’re out of town or on vacation when your cameras run out of battery? Or what if the stores near you don’t carry the &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.blinkforhome.com/customer/en/portal/articles/2150051-what-kind-of-batteries-does-blink-use-are-they-eas
y-to-replace-&#34;&gt;specific
lithium
batteries&lt;/a&gt; Blink cameras need to function properly? With Sensr.net, you’re given the freedom to choose from thousands of
cameras. So no matter if you want a camera that draws power from a battery, an electrical outlet, or even &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Waterproof-Wireless-ONVIF2-1-Surveillance-Security/dp/B018QA5X70/sensr-20&#34;&gt;the
sun&lt;/a&gt;, Sensr.net has you
covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;storage&#34;&gt;Storage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blink’s cloud storage service is free once you purchase one of their cameras. This sounds great, until you realize that you’re limited to storing only two hours of video. That’s not even a full day of surveillance! On top of that, Blink doesn’t even give you the option to pay for more storage, so no matter what you’re stuck with a mere 120 minutes of storage. Sensr.net, on the other hand, offers a full month of cloud storage for only $9. That’s nearly 365 times more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;camera&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you decide to use Blink’s service, you only have two bundles to choose from; The Blink indoor system and the upgraded Blink
XT system. The XT camera has motion detection, infrared night vision, temperature sensing, is weatherproof, and the bundle
includes two hours of cloud video storage, all for $129. Sounds reasonable, right? Well, with those 129 dollars, you could
instead get &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/ieGeek-Wireless-Security-Outdoor-Surveillance/dp/B01JLZKSD8/sensr-20&#34;&gt;this $45 camera&lt;/a&gt; which
has the same features as the XT camera (minus temperature sensing), a whole 8 months of Sensr.net service with 30 days of cloud
video storage, and even after all that, you’d still have $4.40 left over. You could save even more if you opted for our yearly
subscription plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;api&#34;&gt;API&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sensr.net also allows advanced users to build their own programs using our SDK. Using our API, enthusiasts can write their own
code that can access camera data from Sensr’s cloud. Want to build your own iPhone app? Write in facial recognition? Go for it.
While it’s not exactly something that the everyday user would want, it’s still there for anyone who needs it.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/SensrBlinkChart.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Sensr vs Blink comparison Chart&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The great news is that we offer free trials to all who are interested. If you like what you see, and we are sure you will, you can sign up for your own account and regain the control of your Wi-Fi security cameras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;wrap-up&#34;&gt;Wrap up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Sensr.net, we seek to be the best nest cam alternative available that is both user friendly and flexible in the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try us today for free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Alternative to Nest Cam</title>
      <link>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/05/an-alternative-to-nest-cam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 09:00:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sensr.net/2017/05/an-alternative-to-nest-cam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/nest-cam.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Nest Cam Indoor HD Camera&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;No doubt about it, Nest Cam is easy to setup and use.  But there are a number of drawbacks to using Nest Cam
that might entice you to try an alternative like &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt;.  Here are some reasons that you
might want to try an alternative to Nest Cam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t use your own camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t mix and match camera models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The service is expensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No APIs for accessing your footage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Locked in to one vendor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited video clips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in using Sensr.net as an alternative to using Nest Cam, give us a try.  We have a
free trial of course.  Any you can use almost any camera with our service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s go into the details of why you might want an alternative to Nest Cam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;flexible-camera-choice&#34;&gt;Flexible camera choice&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time with Nest Cam you had only one choice, an indoor camera. Now Nest Cam comes in two flavors, indoor
and outdoor. But what if you don&amp;rsquo;t like these solutions? Besides being expensive, the form factor just might not fit
your needs. What if you want a dome camera? Or a camera that you can pan, tilt, and zoom? PTZ (pan, tilt, zoom)
cameras are very common but Nest doesn&amp;rsquo;t have one. What if you want a telephoto lens or a spy camera? Sorry, but
with Nest Cam you&amp;rsquo;re out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get HD security cameras on Amazon for under $40. Nest Cam starts at $199. If you&amp;rsquo;re technically savvy and
don&amp;rsquo;t mind doing a little work in setting up the camera, you can use a service like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt;Sensr.net&lt;/a&gt; for your Cloud DVR with your $40 camera and save a lot of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Sensr.net you can even use cameras from different manufacturers.  You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be stuck to one brand.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/SensrNestCompare.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;With Sensr.net you can use almost any camera!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;limited-video-clips&#34;&gt;Limited Video Clips&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Nest Cam you&amp;rsquo;re limited to 3 hours of clips. On Sensr.net we don&amp;rsquo;t limit the number of &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2014/04/29/making-clips-on-sensr-net/&#34;&gt;clips you
make&lt;/a&gt;. We store them on our servers as long as you have a valid account. We
also email you a link to download the clip every time you make one. You&amp;rsquo;ll have your own copy and can do anything
you want with it. Give it to the police, stick it in your Dropbox folder for future reference, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;flexible-and-programmatic-access&#34;&gt;Flexible and Programmatic access&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Sensr.net you can use &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/2013/02/07/new-sensr-net-api-v3/&#34;&gt;our APIs&lt;/a&gt; to write code to access your camera data
that is stored in the cloud. Don&amp;rsquo;t like how we generate clips? Write your own code to do a better job. Sure, this is
not a feature that most users will want, but we think it&amp;rsquo;s kind of cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limited-storage&#34;&gt;Limited storage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nest Cam will give you 10 days of storage for $10. For the same price with Sensr.net you get a month of storage. We
also give you unlimited storage of favorites images and clips. Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/plans&#34;&gt;our pricing&lt;/a&gt; for
more details. We have annual plans that save you even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.sensr.net/img/SensrNestChart.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;With Sensr.net you can use almost any camera!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you like the idea of using a Cloud DVR for your security cameras, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to be locked in to one
camera brand, make sure you explore other alternatives and give Sensr.net a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;cta&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sensr.net/auth/users/sign_up&#34;&gt; &lt;button&gt; Sign up for free! &lt;/button&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Best Nest Cam Alternative Yet written by: Vation
The Best Nest Cam Alternative Yet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you tired of your nest cam? Are you exhausted from paying so much money only to have about 3 hours of clipping, does 10 days for 10 dollars seem a bit pricey to you? Well, we got you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At sensr, we seek to provide you with cloud dvr storage of your choice, for a price you won’t help but want to pay and guess what? It’s all up to your personal preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who Are We?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a wifi security camera and cloud dvr storage company that seek to provide security camera users with a cheaper and more interesting alternative to nest cam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why Us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side by side comparison:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nest cam Sensr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· One vendor As many as you prefer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Single camera Multiple cameras&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Expensive Affordable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Limited clip time Limitless clip time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Limited storage Limitless cloud dvr storage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full review:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your camera, your choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, most users who needed surveillance were stuck with the option of the camera provided by the company. This sometimes meant that they had to pay for expensive cameras which may not have provided them with the kind of clarity or footage quality they wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At sensr, we give our clients the flexibility of choosing the Ip camera they want. This is based on the fact that there are some amazing Ip cameras online that do not necessarily cost a fortune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our clients can also mix camera from different manufacturers however they please. We seek to ensure that the client’s happiness is what comes first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As many clips as you want, as long as you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the older providers limited the number of video clips to a maximum of 3hours, we allow you as our user to create as many clips as you want without the constraint of having to worry about what is important and what is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage, storage, storage!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world existing in cloud storage, we provide the best there is in cloud dvr. Our servers can hold as much data as you want them to at a price that is affordable. Check our pricing here (). These service is available to you as long as you have a valid email account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great news is that the longer the plan you choose, the greater the save.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access your clippings at the touch of a button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With nest came and the other alternatives, you only found as much of your clippings as they could provide. With sensr, however, all the data is available to you using our APIs. These allow you to code for access to our cloud storage. There is also the option of generating your own codes however way you please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affordable for all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a variety of plans available that are great for first time beginners, indoor and outdoor lighting and all scenarios which may not have been addressed with the older security cameras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free trials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great news is that we offer free trials to all who are interested. If you like what you see, and we are sure you will, you can sign up for your own account and regain the control of your Wi-Fi security cameras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrap up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At sensr, we seek to be the best nest cam alternative available that is both user friendly and flexible in the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try us today for free!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>